<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Movies on Raymond Camden</title>
    <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/categories/movies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Movies on Raymond Camden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 10:25:47 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.raymondcamden.com/categories/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Media in 2015</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/28/favorite-media-in-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 10:25:47 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/28/favorite-media-in-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following up on my previous non-tech/just for fun posts (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/23/books-i-read-in-2015&#34;&gt;Books I Read in 2015&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/22/my-year&#34;&gt;My Year&lt;/a&gt;), here is my favorite media of 2015. This was originally going to be my favorite music of the year, but I figured I&amp;rsquo;d expand it a bit to cover movies and video games too. This is obviously a very personal list, but hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll get some ideas about things to watch/play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Favorite Music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is in no particular order, but here are the tracks I listened to a &lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt; this year. The first track, &amp;ldquo;Close Your Eyes&amp;rdquo;, is incredible. I first heard it on Sirius XMU and was just blown away. It sounds like a pop/rap/NIN mashup and is a great song to turn up real, real loud - just be sure the kids aren&amp;rsquo;t around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PkGwI7nGehA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of mashups, my favorite this year was a mix of NIN and Taylor Swift. The video is really well done too. Even better, my 5 year old just loves the hell out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DhvXST1Rc3g&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another surprise was the new Prodigy album - the first single was freaking awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/h1AaKBbNGkk&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently, this Grimes track has been on repeat for me as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Tv9YoYCKNoE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while not new, my favorite song from the past few years has been pretty consistent - &amp;ldquo;Wings&amp;rdquo; by HAERTS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yk52XHSpmF4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Movies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, the &lt;i&gt;big&lt;/i&gt; movie for me was - obviously - the Force Awakens. I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/18/review-star-wars-the-force-awakens&#34;&gt;reviewed&lt;/a&gt; it already. But what else impressed me this year? I thought both &amp;ldquo;Avengers 2&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Ant-Man&amp;rdquo; were great Marvel films. I liked how different they were. One was a huge scale/popcorn chomping film while the other was much smaller, personable, still with great action. And while I&amp;rsquo;m not specifically writing up a TV section, &amp;ldquo;Jessica Jones&amp;rdquo; was &lt;i&gt;damn&lt;/i&gt; good too. As an aside, Netflix is the best thing to happen to TV in a long time. From their own content to their documentary selection to even some of their &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; flicks, I feel like I could easily pay more for the service. Speaking of Marvel - don&amp;rsquo;t bother seeing the Fantastic Four film. It isn&amp;rsquo;t watchable even if you can see it for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Inside Out&amp;rdquo; was easily one of the best children&amp;rsquo;s movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen since &amp;ldquo;Up&amp;rdquo;. I loved &amp;ldquo;The Martian&amp;rdquo; and will be reading the book next year. &amp;ldquo;The Visit&amp;rdquo; proved to me that M.Night &lt;i&gt;may&lt;/i&gt; have a tiny bit of talent left (stress - &amp;ldquo;may&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was initially a bit disappointed by &amp;ldquo;Mad Max&amp;rdquo;, but after watching it a second time I appreciate it a bit more. I still feel like it was more a &amp;ldquo;Film set in the Mad Max universe&amp;rdquo; then a proper &amp;ldquo;Mad Max&amp;rdquo; film, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just being too picky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one film I&amp;rsquo;d like folks to consider, it is &amp;ldquo;Maggie&amp;rdquo;. This flew &lt;i&gt;way&lt;/i&gt; under the radar - I don&amp;rsquo;t think I saw it advertised once - but it is an incredibly well done zombie film. Outside of &amp;ldquo;The Walking Dead&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m really tired of zombies, but this is the best zombie film I&amp;rsquo;ve seen since &amp;ldquo;28 Days Later.&amp;rdquo; I highly recommend seeing &amp;ldquo;Maggie&amp;rdquo; as soon as you can. I never thought I&amp;rsquo;d see a zombie film that was slow and thoughtful - but this movie really pulls if off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2xSzwS_wK-0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and as for stuff I&amp;rsquo;m embarrassed to admit - my guilty pleasure recently is &amp;ldquo;The Royals.&amp;rdquo; It is pure and utter trash, but fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/t1XvUYvdr3s&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For next year, keep an eye out for &amp;ldquo;Colony&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of alien invasion stories, especially ones that are far removed from &amp;ldquo;Independence Day&amp;rdquo;, and this one looks fascinating so far. You can watch the first episode online now if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to wait. Of course, like most sci-fi shows with a &amp;ldquo;mystery&amp;rdquo;, you have to assume it will probably get cancelled before they resolve anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oRLW-qQLMQs&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Video Games&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I just checked, and apparently, I only reviewed 2 video games this year - Battlefront and Destiny. I liked them both, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d consider them great. I&amp;rsquo;m spending a &lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt; of time during this Christmas break playing Fallout 4, and I like it a lot too, but again, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;ll be thinking about it in a year&amp;rsquo;s time. As an example of what I mean - my eldest son recently borrowed my PS3 (the PS4 now rules my TV) so he could play &amp;ldquo;The Last of Us&amp;rdquo;, and I still tend to think of that game when I think about what makes a truly &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo; video game. (And if folks are curious, my all time favorite game was &amp;ldquo;A Mind Forever Voyaging&amp;rdquo;.) I guess the best I can say is that I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying the three games I mentioned and I recommend them, but nothing has blown me away this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will add that both Sony and Microsoft have deals where if you pay for a yearly multiplayer subscription, you get free games every month. While the quality goes up and down, there have been some really great freebies. So even if you don&amp;rsquo;t play online a lot, you should definitely consider subscribing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Star Wars - The Force Awakens</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/18/review-star-wars-the-force-awakens</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 13:47:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/18/review-star-wars-the-force-awakens</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/tfa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tfa&#34; width=&#34;270&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-7270&#34; style=&#34;margin-right:10px&#34; /&gt; Normally I wait till Sunday to do non-tech posts, but with the memory of the film still burning bright in my mind from last night, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write it up today. The first of this review will be &lt;strong&gt;spoiler-free&lt;/strong&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ll clearly mark the beginnings of spoilers. Also, the comments are fair game for spoilers too, so stop reading where it makes sense for you. This will be long winded and emotional, so if you want the tl;dr - it rocked. See it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My memories of the first Star Wars film are a bit hazy. I was four years so I&amp;rsquo;m not even terribly sure I&amp;rsquo;m remembering correctly. All I know is that I saw it with my father and the only scene I remember is R2 being lowered into X-Wing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Empire Strikes Back, all I remember is the line. It stretched around the movie theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Return of the Jedi, I saw it in a little town in Louisiana. There were - maybe - five people in the theater and I sat in the very first row. (Don&amp;rsquo;t ask me why - I was a dumb kid.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Star Wars fan for as long as I can remember. I&amp;rsquo;ve certainly seen better sci fi in my life, but nothing has left the impression on me as much as these movies. I love them - warts and all. When I ride my bike, I&amp;rsquo;m flying through the woods of Endor. As I write this - I&amp;rsquo;m in an office completely covered in Star Wars toys. (And some Star Trek too - along with Robotech and a few other geeky properties.) For the past few years I&amp;rsquo;ve walked my kids to school in a full on Sith robe with a fancy (i.e. not cheap) light saber. I&amp;rsquo;m actually considering picking up some boots/pants to make it a bit more realistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/ray.png&#34; alt=&#34;ray&#34; width=&#34;268&#34; height=&#34;475&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-7271&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah - I love Star Wars. &lt;i&gt;Really&lt;/i&gt; love it. So when I heard about the new trilogy, I was pretty damn excited. Unlike a lot of Star Wars fans, I did not hate the prequels. Did they come close to what I, and many other fans, had hoped for? Not at all. To be fair, there was no chance in hell it could. And in the end, Vader&amp;rsquo;s portrayal was a let down. That being said, the prequels had some great aspects to it. Without a doubt, Ewan McGregor absolutely, 100%, nailed Obi Wan. Ian McDiarmid&amp;rsquo;s Palaptine was wonderfully evil. His scene with Anakin at the Space Opera was chilling. The Jedi being portrayed as all powerful, yet seemingly blind, has been called one of the flaws of the prequels, but to me, this is one of the strengths. They had grown complacent and I think that made for a great part of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also didn&amp;rsquo;t have the Special Editions. To me - they let me see the movies again on the big screen - and actually remember them this time. Did I like seeing Greedo shoot first? Nope. Did I loose any sleep over it? Nope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest concern with the new movie was it turning into something cool, but lacking in the original spirit of the movies. I enjoyed JJ Abrams updated Star Trek film, but the more time passes, and the more I watch DS9, the more I feel like he really missed out on the &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo; of Trek. (And yes, I&amp;rsquo;m a huge Trekkie too.) The trailers that were released really felt like they got the emotional aspect right, but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be sure until I actually saw it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as the lights dimmed last night and I saw those famous words on screen - my fears melted away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/long.png&#34; alt=&#34;long&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-7272&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the first sentence of the crawl to the last shot - this was everything I had hoped the prequels would be and every bit a &amp;ldquo;proper&amp;rdquo; Star Wars movie. You&amp;rsquo;ve got great action, incredibly funny scenes, awesome bad guys, and a great story as well. The cast, especially the new heroes, were wonderful. Kylo was incredible. So many movies have trouble getting the bad guys well and I thought he was awesome. I really liked Hux too, even when he was (and maybe this is a spoiler) bat-shit fanatical. Rey and Finn had great chemistry, and while at times they were a bit annoying in their youthful excitement, it was a &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; annoying if that makes sense. As I told a friend, sometimes the jokes were bad - but even when they were bad, I still grinned like a fool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Force Awakens&amp;rdquo; met every expectation I had. I won&amp;rsquo;t call it perfect (and few films are) - but I&amp;rsquo;m so happy now I feel like I can bust. If I had to call out one thing I felt let down by it would have to be the soundtrack. While it was good to hear those old melodies again, not one of the new songs really feels like it made an impression on me. There was no &amp;ldquo;Imperial March&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Duel of Fates&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m going to give it another chance though - I&amp;rsquo;m buying the soundtrack today. But at least while I watched, I can&amp;rsquo;t say that any of the new music was memorable. It certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad, but John Williams has really set the bar high. (The music in the cantina though was pretty good. I&amp;rsquo;m not really counting that as it feels like it is set apart from the soundtrack itself.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously - don&amp;rsquo;t wait - go to the movies today. Now. See it with your kids. Enjoy the hell out of it and lets hope the next movies are just as good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/spoiler-alert.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;spoiler-alert&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-7273&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some random, SPOILER-ish, thoughts in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shot of the Star Destroyer covering the planet as an opening shot was freaking perfect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Kylo stopped the laser in midair I was convinced I wasn&#39;t seeing it. My jaw dropped. That is - single handedly - the coolest thing I&#39;ve seen in a Star Wars movie ever. Or least tied with the reveal of the Super Star Destroyer in ESB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snoke is... fascinating. I don&#39;t recognize his race. He doesn&#39;t seem like &#34;just another Emperor&#34;. Another thing to keep in mind is that Snoke in person could be quite a bit different than what we see in the hologram.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I love the new X-Wings. Love em. But I still wish I had seen an A or B wing too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you didn&#39;t read the books, I bet you would be pretty confused by the &#34;Resistance&#34; thing. To be honest, I&#39;ve read the new books and I still find it a bit weird. From what I know, the New Republic is helping the Resistance fight against the First Order, but why there is a separate group as opposed to just &#34;the military of the Republic&#34; is weird. In &#34;Aftermath&#34;, they suggest heavily that the government is going to be pacifist, but it still feels like an odd setup. The First Order I get. The Empire was shattered, broken apart, and this is what came from it. But the Resistance seems weird. I&#39;ll get over it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love that we have a new Star Destroyer. I find the top portion to be weirdly off center, but that could be my OCD. In case you&#39;re curious, and you are - the SD is the Finalizer. The class is called &lt;a href=&#34;http://starwars.wikia.com/wiki/Resurgent-class_Star_Destroyer&#34;&gt;Resurgent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hux&#39;s speech was so over the top. I would have loved to have been there for the filming of that. Obviously meant to echo Hitler&#39;s speeches, it just shows how this new Empire is much more fanatical, much more a cult than the &#34;dignified while blowing up your planet&#34; days of Tarkin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New TFA Trailer</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/10/20/the-new-tfa-trailer</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 05:58:43 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/10/20/the-new-tfa-trailer</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sure, everyone has seen this probably and you don&amp;rsquo;t need me to share the video here, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to do so anyway - enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sGbxmsDFVnE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I freaking loved it, but that&amp;rsquo;s no surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Second Star Wars Teaser</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/04/16/the-second-star-wars-teaser</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 16:04:32 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/04/16/the-second-star-wars-teaser</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to write a blog post on IndexedDB today - instead I got royally distracted by the &lt;strong&gt;epic cool new Star Wars&lt;/strong&gt; teaser:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;853&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ngElkyQ6Rhs?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; much to love in this. I love how the opening shot is reminiscent of ANH&amp;rsquo;s landspeeder shot. I love the crashed Star Destroyer. And then things just get better and better. The new Stormtroopers and new Imperial logo (time for a new tattoo!), the new TIE fighters, and more shots of the big bad - Kylo Ren. A new - I think - Star Destroyer type as well. (Seems to have only one shield generator versus two.) And of course - the final shot of Han and Chewie. No - I&amp;rsquo;m not crying - something just got stuck in my eye. Honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t. Freaking. Wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/sstfa.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/sstfa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sstfa&#34; width=&#34;534&#34; height=&#34;831&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-6016&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars Teaser</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/11/28/Star-Wars-Teaser</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 10:11:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/11/28/Star-Wars-Teaser</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&#39;m assuming most people who care have already watched this online, but I&#39;m sharing it anyway. Today the teaser for the next Star Wars film launched and it is incredible. I know a lot of folks hated the prequels and will remind me that the first teaser for them was pretty exciting as well. I don&#39;t care. The prequels were &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; as cool as I had hoped, but frankly, I didn&#39;t mind. I enjoyed them. Not as much as the original series, which by the way, also had its groan-worthy moments, but I had a heck of a lot of fun just watching them. I&#39;m thrilled by what I see here. The Stormtroopers, in particular, look to be bad ass. One of the best parts of the Prequels was seeing the Clone Troopers as an effective fighting force. I&#39;d like to see them kicking butt again in this new series, &lt;i&gt;especially&lt;/i&gt; if we get to see the Empire in the Rebellion&#39;s role from the classic series. Much smaller, much leaner, etc. Any way, enjoy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;366&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/OMOVFvcNfvE?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The movies that scared the crap out of me...</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/10/28/The-movies-that-scared-the-crap-out-of-me</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 13:10:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/10/28/The-movies-that-scared-the-crap-out-of-me</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I did a good &amp;ldquo;Sunday OT&amp;rdquo; post and with Halloween quickly approaching, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share what I consider to be the most scary movies I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. Before jumping into the list though, I need to provide a bit of context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a child, I was interested in the supernatural, specifically Bigfoot and UFOs. I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure why (outside of just being young and slightly less mature than I am now), but I read every book I could find on anything related to cryptozoology and UFO sightings. While it was a good deal of junk &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo;, it was, for the most part, adult level writing, which was probably pretty good for my reading skills as a youth. On the negative side though I can clearly see how it&amp;rsquo;s impacted my fears as an adult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll also point out that I am &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; much not a fan of gore. I can remember watching Hostel and having to turn away at times. Every aspect of that film, and films like it (Saw for example) just felt wrong to me. I can&amp;rsquo;t stomach it. (Although you&amp;rsquo;re going to see one exception to the rule below.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0050095/&#34;&gt;The Abominable Snowman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can remember discovering this film around 12 years old or so. Being that I was a huge Bigfoot fanatic at the time, I was naturally also interesting in the Abominable Snowman. I got even more interested when I noticed that one of the main characters was Peter Cushing, AKA Grand Moff Tarkin. I had expected a fairly simple, old style monster movie. What I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect was a movie that put much more of an emphasis on the mood and environment than silly scenes of men in monster suits. The whole idea of a monster film that skipped the monster was incredible to me at the time. The tension I remember feeling was much more heightened because of what they didn&amp;rsquo;t show compared to what they did. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spoil it, but the ending of this film is creepy as hell. I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen this film since I was 12, and I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it as much now, but at the time it really opened my mind to what could be done by implication and subtlety compared to special effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/Abominable_Snowman_movie.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0084516/&#34;&gt;Poltergeist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone who reads this has scene this film, but pretend for a moment you haven&amp;rsquo;t. If I were to tell you that one of the most chilling scenes in this film involved a &lt;i&gt;tree&lt;/i&gt;, you would probably think I was crazy. I&amp;rsquo;ve got something of a minor phobia when it comes to storms. Minor isn&amp;rsquo;t probably fair. I get &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; nervous when lightning is around, even if I&amp;rsquo;m safe and sound in my home. The storm scene in Poltergeist then is one of the scenes that freaks me out. While there are numerous creepy scenes in the film, I&amp;rsquo;ll also call out the &amp;ldquo;voice in the TV&amp;rdquo; scene as pretty intense too. I rewatched this recently and as a parent, it was even more nerve-wracking to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0097100/&#34;&gt;Communion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not necessarily meant to be a horror film, this &amp;ldquo;supposedly based on true events&amp;rdquo; story of alien visitation was just plain creepy. Of course, anything with Walken is a good film, the scenes where the aliens seem to be in the same house as him and peering around a corner still sends chills down my spine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/szwvjXo_sHQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0185937/&#34;&gt;The Blair Witch Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, I know this movie has almost no middle ground for viewers, but for me, especially with my whole Bigfoot-thing, a film set out in the woods with weird crap going on was pretty scary for me. Yes, you had those obnoxious actors, but the scenes at night with the voices just did something for me. (And by something I mean - of course - scare the crap out of me.) I loved the gradual build up and the lack of any real gore. It made the one small bit of gore all the more effective. I know it started the whole found-film genre that Hollywood has decided to go over the top on, but when it first came out it was an interesting change of style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of films set out in the woods, I&amp;rsquo;ll also point the scene in the Village where the townspeople stood with their backs to the woods was incredibly scary for me as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/Blair_Witch_Project.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0286106/&#34;&gt;Signs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, since I brought up a Shyamalan film, I might as well bring up the one that is - for me - the most creepy. While the Sixth Sense was a much better film and Unbreakable is - easily - one of the most interesting superhero films - it was Signs that crept me out the most. Just about every scene with an alien in this film freaked me out. The film breaks down pretty bad towards the end, but I still find certain scenes in this film scary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/czy4RjcrpFM&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1179904/&#34;&gt;Paranormal Activity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love ghost stories, but they almost always take place in familiar territories - old creepy homes, abandoned hospitals, or mental institutions. What really got me with Paranormal Activity was that it took place in suburbia. Hell, it could have been my neighbor&amp;rsquo;s house. It also made excellent use of sound as well. I absolutely love this film. Even watching it again still creeps me out and I know exactly what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen next. I enjoyed PA2 and 3 as well, and may see 4 too. But I think they are pretty much milking this series dry at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1139797/&#34;&gt;Let the Right One In&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the original Norwegian version, not the remake. If this film taught me anything it&amp;rsquo;s that Norwegians have some serious eff-ed up films. There are things in this film that are more than a little bit uncomfortable to see, but over all, it&amp;rsquo;s an amazingly well-done film. The ending - again - is an amazing example of what can be done when you &lt;i&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/i&gt; show the main action but rather show the effects instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Rest...&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll think of more later, but other films I&amp;rsquo;d add to this list would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alien: For obvious reasons. I rewatched this about a month or so ago and was surprised how quiet the beginning of this film was. So... different from most films. The closest example I can think of is the period in Castaway with no dialog. 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0464141/&#34;&gt;The Orphanage&lt;/a&gt;: A very different, surprising film. 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1038988/&#34;&gt;[Rec]&lt;/a&gt;: Another found-footage film, this one contained within a building with a zombie-esque type flavor to it. I&#39;d also recommend the sequel, which took things in a &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; different direction. 
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh - and I mentioned earlier that I do not like gore. I&amp;rsquo;m going to make one exception to the rule. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1259521/&#34;&gt;The Cabin in the Woods&lt;/a&gt; was marketed as a &amp;ldquo;different&amp;rdquo; type of horror film. The trailers even tend to give you a big idea of what that twist was. But when you actually see the film, you really begin to realize how different this film is. There were parts of this movie so fun/exciting I almost jumped out of my seat. It&amp;rsquo;s my favorite film of 2012 - even more so than the Avengers. While it definitely had gore, it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel gratuitous.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spoiler Talk on Prometheus</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/06/09/Spoiler-Talk-on-Prometheus</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 15:06:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/06/09/Spoiler-Talk-on-Prometheus</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw Prometheus last night. It was cool. Stop reading now if you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it. Seriously - this is your last warning&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/pro.jpg&#34; style=&#34;float: left;margin-right: 10px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I really enjoyed the movie, and some of the shots on the large screen made me &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; happy I was seeing it in a theater. I loved how the show began. In ways, it reminded me of Green Lantern. I know that show wasn&amp;rsquo;t liked by most folks, but I liked how it began in a very alien, sci-fi manner. Ditto for Prometheus. The opening was confusing, alien, and just off-putting. I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now - while I liked the film - here are some things I felt were a bit off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One - why in the hell would David do an experiment on the scientist? I mean - I get that the Company (Weyland) has long been shown to be uncaring, cruel, etc. Fine. But it seems incredibly random and dangerous to just drop some black goo into a human and see what happens, &lt;i&gt;especially&lt;/i&gt; while your millions of miles away from home. Sure, as an android he may not have much to fear, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see why he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have just kept the &amp;lsquo;jug&amp;rsquo; in storage until the return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two - the guy who went crazy. That seemed odd and out of place. It seemed clear to me that the main mode of attack for these creatures was to burrow into the body and gestate. But for this one guy it made him super strong and homicidal. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three - not a nit pick, but I loved the Engineers. I loved the design of their ship. I loved the user interface for the ship. I especially loved that they were incomprehensible, uncaring, evil bastards. Evil may not even make sense. Perhaps to them we were nothing more than defective robots. But I just love that we got no real clear answers from them on why they wanted to destroy us. It felt cruel&amp;hellip; and perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally - the last scene was amazing. I loved the &amp;lsquo;proto-Alien&amp;rsquo; creature. The movies have shown that the creatures were adaptable based on their host, so this may actually have been the &amp;lsquo;final&amp;rsquo; evolution of them. But it was just amazing. I was perfectly happy with all the more subtle connections to the Alien series. To be honest, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need this scene to be satisfied with the film. That being said though I was on the edge of my seat once I realized what was happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what did you guys think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br clear=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to me about Green Lantern (non-spoiler)</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2011/06/18/Talk-to-me-about-Green-Lantern-nonspoiler</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2011 22:06:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2011/06/18/Talk-to-me-about-Green-Lantern-nonspoiler</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/cfjedi/green_lantern.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Green Lantern. He&#39;s green and has a light&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;margin-right:10px&#34; /&gt; I just got out of seeing Green Lantern with my boys. (My eldest loved it. Said it was the best film he had seen all year.) I have to say - despite all the negative reviews I heard - I really enjoyed it. It was early in the film when I figured out exactly why. Movies like Iron Man and Thor - and I assume Captain America to come - are all &amp;ldquo;Films based on Comics.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s great. But Green Lantern felt like a &amp;ldquo;Comic Book Movie.&amp;rdquo; When you spend the first five minutes or so deep into cosmology and aliens you&amp;rsquo;re in an entirely different world than what you get with Iron Man. Shoot, even with Asgard in Thor, Green Lantern just felt a lot more &amp;lsquo;comicy&amp;rsquo;. (Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m creating that word. I own it and will be charging royalties.) Green Lantern is far from perfect. A lot of the romance felt like - well - comic book romance. It also spends a surprisingly large amount of time away from the main character. That being said, I really enjoyed it. I was never a Green Lantern reader so I can&amp;rsquo;t comment on how well it pays homage to the comic. I can say I&amp;rsquo;m considering picking up the comic - especially with DC about to reset everything in a month or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So - what did folks think? (And please - try to keep it spoiler free!)
&lt;br clear=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Tron Legacy</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2010/12/21/Thoughts-on-Tron-Legacy</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2010 00:12:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2010/12/21/Thoughts-on-Tron-Legacy</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/cfjedi/405px-Tronlegacy.jpg.jpg&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;margin-right:10px&#34; /&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s rather late - but my eldest boy is keeping me up so we can see the eclipse in another hour so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d do a quick write up of my thoughts on Tron Legacy. Everything above the word SPOILER will be spoiler free. Anything below, including comments, should be considered free reign for anything folks want to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few movies from my youth that hold a warm spot in my heart. Star Wars (and Empire and Jedi of course) are one of them obviously. Tron is another. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;d probably say Tron had the biggest impact on me as a young computer programmer. Tron came out in 1982. I was 9 then and to be honest - I don&amp;rsquo;t remember if I had even used a computer at that point. But I remember being in awe of the special effects and even more so - at the idea of a living, breathing world inside of computers. I know that when I did begin to program (Apple IIe FTW!) that the idea of my programs being actual living creatures was always there in my mind. All thanks to Tron of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tron was one of those magical films of my youth. I had no expectations that Tron Legacy would be magical. Computers aren&amp;rsquo;t a brave new world for kids today. My own kids are living in a house where our phones have more power than I had until college. Right now my eldest is next to me on an older Macbook Pro while I type on a laptop and another desktop is about 10 feet away. My wife&amp;rsquo;s laptop is nearby as well. That&amp;rsquo;s 4 machines in this room alone. I certainly don&amp;rsquo;t think anything is wrong with that - but a lot of the magic of the original Tron is something that can&amp;rsquo;t quite be recreated today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with that in mind, my hopes were simple. Let me see what transpired in the world of Tron and let me be impressed by the visual design and effects. As cool as Tron was in terms of CGI, a lot of the iconic designs are what impress me today. Take the Recognizer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/cfjedi/Reco.PNG&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty simplistic - but I remember being in awe of them on the big screen and they still look menacing to me today. The entire movie was full of design choices that just&amp;hellip; felt right. And this is where Tron Legacy succeeds well. Obviously the effects are top notch. But frankly, we live in a world where crap SyFy shows have more than passable decent CGI. Tron Legacy does a good job by both being impressive and imaginative. The updated Recognizer reminds me of comparing Windows 7 to 95. You can see a similar hand in the creation of both but the newer model is quite a bit shiner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is full of many nods to the past. When Sam first returns to his father&amp;rsquo;s arcade and turns on the power - the wave of nostalgia was overwhelming. I love my XBox 360. But growing up I spent a heck of a lot of time in arcades. The &amp;ldquo;wall of sound&amp;rdquo; you experience surrounded by a hundred or so arcade machines is just not something you experience now. The movie captured it perfectly. Unfortunately it will probably mean nothing to most kids today. The actual plot - and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a spoiler to say that most of it occurs in the digital world - is a bit muddled at times. This is a show about the visuals above all else. But there was certainly as much depth as Avatar and most other films. This is no &amp;ldquo;Inception&amp;rdquo;, but there was enough of a narrative to keep me interested in between the hyper-kinetic action scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let&amp;rsquo;s not kid around. I can remember the first time I saw the light cycle scene in the original film. The new light cycle scene is &lt;b&gt;damn&lt;/b&gt; good. It&amp;rsquo;s not just &amp;lsquo;prettier&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s like moving from 2D to 3D (literally in terms of game play for the characters). The action scenes in Tron Legacy are both high paced and just darn plain cool looking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all - I enjoyed Tron Legacy. Will it be as good for folks who don&amp;rsquo;t have quite have such fond memories of the original? Probably not. But even then it&amp;rsquo;s worth seeing on the big screen. (I can only comment on the 2D showing though. Frankly I&amp;rsquo;m sick and tired of this 3D bull crap and I&amp;rsquo;m going to do my best to not put any more money into a 3D showing if I can help it.) I&amp;rsquo;d recommend seeing it - but if you&amp;rsquo;ve not yet made time to ever watch the original, do try to do so first. It will add quite a bit of context and make for a more complete viewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, stop reading now if you want to avoid spoilers&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SPOILER&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few things in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love how a company that is made out to be like Microsoft has a grand total of &lt;b&gt;one fracking rent-a-cop guard&lt;/b&gt;. Seriously? One guard?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love how the fact that the OS was leaked on the Internet was a big deal. Aren&amp;rsquo;t all OSes leaked on the net? And isn&amp;rsquo;t it not much of a big deal outside of us nerds? I doubt if more than 2% of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s customer base know what a torrent is and would have any clue that a leaked version would exist on the net.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you notice the OS was &amp;ldquo;OS 12&amp;rdquo; - a Mac shout out? Sam also had a Mac as a child. If any computer is a dystopia on the inside it&amp;rsquo;s a Mac. ;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;One incredibly creepy scene: In the night club, after the violence has started, note the quick shot of a woman holding the &amp;ldquo;bits&amp;rdquo; of her lover and crying in agony. That came out of nowhere and surprised the hell out of me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Absolutely loved the music. Daft Punk&amp;rsquo;s sound track is great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of sound - there were more then one throw back to the old movies. During the light cycle game the sound was a direct reference to the first movie. That really sold the scene for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clu&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;creepy&amp;rdquo; young Jeff Bridges was great. If there was ever a case of where the &amp;ldquo;dead behind the eyes&amp;rdquo; look works - then this is it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really with the Iso&amp;rsquo;s background had been fleshed out a tiny bit more. It felt forced. One or two more lines of dialog would have really helped here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Loved Flynn&amp;rsquo;s line about how he had the original idea for wifi. Speaking of Flynn - I liked him in general. His whole vibe was very much like a man out place in the modern world. It really worked well in the film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alas - I still miss the MCP. My number one complaint about the Matrix series is that when we do see the big bad guy - it&amp;rsquo;s an boring old white man. To me - nothing will ever be as cool as the big giant spinning MCP. I&amp;rsquo;d kill to see that on the big screen again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee talk about Avatar</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2009/12/20/Coffee-talk-about-Avatar</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2009 21:12:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2009/12/20/Coffee-talk-about-Avatar</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/cfjedi/Avatar-Teaser-Poster.jpg&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; title=&#34;Avatar&#34; style=&#34;margin-right:5px;margin-bottom:5px&#34; /&gt; I just got back from seeing Avatar, the latest film from James Cameron. I won&amp;rsquo;t call this a review - just a smattering of thoughts - but I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear what others thought. Let&amp;rsquo;s keep it spoiler free though. Overall, I thought it was a good film, a strong film, but not quite great. It tried real hard, but in the end, the story was lacking enough for me to keep it from being great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technologically, the film is perfect. Seriously - this film has set the bar for special effects, and probably will be the film by which others are judged. The Na&amp;rsquo;vi looked realistic enough for to be 100% believable. You didn&amp;rsquo;t have any of the &amp;ldquo;Dead on the Inside&amp;rdquo; type feeling you get from other movies with computer generated characters (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, Polar Express).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3D was also well done. You had none of the &amp;ldquo;in your eye&amp;rdquo; type shots to remind you of the 3D, and in fact, except for a few scenes, I pretty much forgot that there was any 3D at all. There was one scene with insects though that - I swear - almost made me raise my hand to bat them away. This is how 3D should be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So from a special effects angle, the movie gets an A+. Shoot, higher than that. I really think it was perfect in that regards. It&amp;rsquo;s the story that&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t know. It just didn&amp;rsquo;t rock my world. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a bad story. Not at all. In fact, when I realized that the movie had lasted over two hours I was truly surprised. The movie never dragged or got boring. Some of the mysticism did get a bit corny at times, but I could live with that. No - what I didn&amp;rsquo;t like was how&amp;hellip; simple the story was. It seems like something we&amp;rsquo;ve seen many times before. Big bad corporation, evil military forces, face off against a technologically inferior but more spiritually aware native force. It just felt&amp;hellip; easy. Too simple. I mean, there was one offhand remark by Jake (the main character) where he mentions that there is no more green on Earth, that it is dead. If the corporation were mining something that Earthlings desperately needed to survive as a race, well, at least we&amp;rsquo;d have some complexity, some  deepness to the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy the story. Really. And I can see buying it (I bet it will be stellar in Blu-Ray), but I wish that some of the subtlety and innovation that was brought to the special effects had been put to work to the story as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so that&amp;rsquo;s my non-review. One last note. I &lt;i&gt;love&lt;/i&gt; ship and vehicle design in Sci-Fi movies. The first shot of the film - the long range ship that beings Jake to Pandora, was incredible. It had a classic 60s feel to the design. Very unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and one last last note. Did folks catch the anti-Bush/anti-Iraq war one-liner in there? Ugh. While I may agree with the politics, it had the subtlety of a brick to the side of that head.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2009/07/17/Review-Harry-Potter-and-the-Half-Blood-Prince</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 23:07:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2009/07/17/Review-Harry-Potter-and-the-Half-Blood-Prince</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As always, I will divide this review into two sections. The top portion will be spoiler free. Everything after the &lt;b&gt;SPOILERS!&lt;/b&gt; mark will be, well, full of spoilers, and I&amp;rsquo;d assume the comments will be as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going in to this film, I was worried. I had heard many good things about this adaption, but frankly, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t convinced they could convey the proper tone for the book. Sure, Harry Potter 1 was all magic, smiles, and laughter, but things have progressively gotten darker and moodier. For me, Goblet of Fire, almost stands out as the Empire Strikes Back of the series. It&amp;rsquo;s the turning point where the laughs kinda die off and the body count begins. What I love most about the series is that it goes from light-hearted magical fair to a much more serious, emotional, and frankly, painful story. To Rowling&amp;rsquo;s credit, she never turned the book &amp;ldquo;adult.&amp;rdquo; There isn&amp;rsquo;t sex, gratuitous violence, or other cop outs. Rowling moves the series expertly along as the characters age and the stakes rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back to my worry. The books convey this pain, this fear, so well, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure the movie could pull it off - especially the pivotal ending. Happily - they did it. Obviously a lot was cut out. But I think the movie did a fair job of striking a balance between length and representing the book. This movie is sad. Overwhelmingly so. And I&amp;rsquo;m happy they kept it like that. There is no &amp;ldquo;Hollywood&amp;rdquo; cop out here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a fan of the series, and maybe felt a little let down by the last movie, definitely see this one. It&amp;rsquo;s worth seeing on a big screen. You &lt;i&gt;may&lt;/i&gt; not want to bring your youngest. I brought all my kids, and while there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything objectionable (even with all the teenage hormones), the movie may drag a bit for them. Again, it&amp;rsquo;s more dark, more serious, than the previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;SPOILERS!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, there are 3 critical parts of the entire series. The death of what&amp;rsquo;s his name at the end of Goblet of Fire, the death of Dumbledore, and the revelation of Snape at the end of B7. I thought Snape&amp;rsquo;s history in Order of the Phoenix wasn&amp;rsquo;t handled well. But they handled his character great here. Ditto Malfoy. The movie did a great job conveying how tortured he felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene with the bridge in the beginning was incredible. It was a great way to demonstrate how the Muggle world was being impacted as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do wish they had spent a bit more time on Voldemort&amp;rsquo;s past. They didn&amp;rsquo;t do a bad job - that young kid was perfect (remind anyone of Damien or the Omen or whatever that old movie was?) and I wish they had maybe cut a bit more of the teenage hormone stuff and spent more on him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Star Trek</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2009/05/08/Review-Star-Trek</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 23:05:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2009/05/08/Review-Star-Trek</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/cfjedi//st.jpg&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;margin-right:10px;margin-bottom:10px&#34;&gt; Before I get into my thoughts about the Star Trek reboot, let me be clear. Any and all spoilers will be marked as such, and will be at the end of the blog entry. So if you just want to know what I thought, you can read the blog entry up until the warning block and turn away. As for comments, I say anything goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, folks know I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat of a Star Wars nut (the whole cfjedimaster, the tats, etc), but I am a fan of Stat Trek as well. I&amp;rsquo;ve watched pretty much all the episodes that ever aired (except for Voyager, back when it was on air it was a busy time in my life, but I have every intention of watching them one day) and have seen all the movies. The quality is not always there. I think any Star Trek fan can attest to that. Shoot, I know there are Star Trek films I can&amp;rsquo;t even describe because they are so forgettable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as a whole, the mythos, the story at large, is darn good. I love the rich history. (I know a lot of people didn&amp;rsquo;t like Enterprise, but I&amp;rsquo;ll always have a great appreciation for the depth it gave to the early Human/Vulcan relationship.) I love the ship designs. (I especially like how they warp theory impacts the shape of the ships and can be seen in the all the different cultures designs.) But most of all - I love the &lt;i&gt;feel&lt;/i&gt; of Star Trek. Much has been said about the general optimism of the Star Trek universe, and I definitely agree with that. There is something personable, warm, and just generally emotional about Star Trek that I don&amp;rsquo;t get from Star Wars. This is what I wanted from the reboot. I knew the special effects would rock. I knew there would be twists and nods to the past (and there was one in particular that is a great nod to Kahn fans). What I really was worried about was how well the show would capture the feeling of Trek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, the movie succeeds. The characters are dead on. I especially liked Kirk. He is an ass. An overconfident jerk. But you know what - this is precisely how I imagined him as a younger person. The actor (Chrine Pine) nails the role, much like Ewan McGregor nailed Obi-Wan. Ditto for Sylar&amp;hellip; err.. sorry, I mean Zachary Quinto, as Spock. We get to see a bit of his upbringing on Vulcan and I thought it was great. Bones was good. Everyone else.. well. They were ok. I don&amp;rsquo;t think they brought much to the characters outside of basic imitation. Chekov was basically a Russian accent joke. Again, they weren&amp;rsquo;t bad, just&amp;hellip; nothing new. Although my son (who is South Korean) got real happy when Sulu had a scene kicking ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story itself was pretty good. Very fast packed, full of action. But (mild spoiler) it does involve time travel, and frankly, I feel like Trek falters whenever they introduce characters hopping through time. However, this does give us a logical way to pretend none of the earlier movies ever happened, and frankly, that may be a good thing. It is a bit of a stretch to see so many young people at the helm of a ship. I have a hard time believing that no one over 30 works in Star Fleet. But I&amp;rsquo;m an old fart so I don&amp;rsquo;t really count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked this movie. It was fun. It had some great nods to the old series (maybe a bit too much), and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the next film. It&amp;rsquo;s a good beginning, but I hope they can kick it up a bit more in the next edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest disappointment though is truly a small thing, but it kind saddened me. The title screen. I know, the title screen/opening credits aren&amp;rsquo;t really that important, but, the fact that the Star Trek theme wasn&amp;rsquo;t used was just kind of&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t know. Sad. It felt like an essential thing was missing. Maybe this will sound sappy, but I always watched the intros to Star Trek, even when I had them on tape. I always found them uplifting. In the movie, the title screen is about 30 seconds and just plain bland. Again, this is a very minor thing - 30 seconds of a 2 hour movie. But I did feel a bit cheated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ok, consider yourself warned. Spoilers are after this.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Am I wrong, or was this the very first time we see a black hole in a Star Trek show? Black holes and bathrooms - they just never show up. But this movie had a bunch of em. Anyone know why black holes were never used?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) The bad guys. Ugh. I felt like they were a bunch of bikers. These weren&amp;rsquo;t Romulans. These were&amp;hellip; white trash. I don&amp;rsquo;t know. Star Wars pretty much sucked on handling the bad guys as well. The Romulan race are proud, haughty, just rich for material and they were handled so poorly here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Not even one Klingon? Oh, and Uhuru hears about 47 Klingon ships being destroyed, and that doesn&amp;rsquo;t scare the crap out of the Federation? I mean, think back to the Cold War. If we heard that half the Russian fleet sunk by some mysterious attacked, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t we be a bit concerned?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) The bad guys show up at Vulcan, and no one else is there? I get that the Federation fleet was busy. But&amp;hellip; um&amp;hellip; you send &lt;i&gt;every&lt;/i&gt; ship away? You don&amp;rsquo;t keep a few ships around your planet for - well just in case?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) The scene with Kirk as a young kid - stealing the car. Perfect. Absolutely perfect. That sold me on the Kirk character in this movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) One thing I never quite got. Maybe this is talked about in one of the numerous books/comics/or whatever. So in the early 21st century there was a nuclear war. Yet someone how we rebuilt. Look at San Francisco in the movie. It looked beautiful. Was it not nuked? Did we maybe discover some way to clear up radiation that - as far as I know, lasts for thousands and thousands of year? Where are all the scars from the horrible war that almost ended humanity? That could have been a good movie. Start off with the Eugenics Wars (I believe it was called that), reboot Kahn, and skip ahead to the modern time of the Federation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) Kobemashu Maru (yes, I spelled it wrong) was done very well. I loved how it setup the antagonism between Kirk and Spock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) Old Spock. Well&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t know. As I said, time travel stories tend to not work well for me in the Star Trek universe. I felt like his acting was a bit rushed. And&amp;hellip; seriously - he didn&amp;rsquo;t arrive in time to help Romulus? What - no one knew the star was going to supernova? There weren&amp;rsquo;t any astronomers on Romulus? I mean maybe that was implied. Maybe most of the people got off the planet. But it felt like Nero was saying most of the race was killed off. If so, they were a bunch of idiots.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to see something really scary?</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2008/10/26/Want-to-see-something-really-scary</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 14:10:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2008/10/26/Want-to-see-something-really-scary</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s almost Halloween and this year I&amp;rsquo;m trying my best to enjoy it as much as possible. Halloween seems to be slowly fading away as everything seems to be pushing towards Christmas insanely early. Sure Halloween is more a kids thing, and maybe I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t care as much now that I&amp;rsquo;m an old guy, but I &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; feel like getting into the mood this year. I visited a haunted house earlier in the week. Our house is decorated (my wife found some awesome and unique decorations this year) and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to go out trick or treating with my young ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgive the rambling. I brought all this up because I wanted to talk about movies. Scary movies. Growing up I was a big horror fan, but in the last ten years or so I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself really turned off by gore. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why exactly. When I watched Hostel, I found myself disgusted and had to turn away multiple times. Maybe it has something to do with my kids. Most horror films involve young kids and I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to watch a modern horror film without thinking that those could be my kids up there. Or maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just a wuss!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;rsquo;t care for horror films, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; getting into the more subtle, suspenseful films. I can remember watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0050095/&#34;&gt;The Adominable Snowman&lt;/a&gt; when I was a young kid. (Staring Peter Cushing, the future Grand Moff Tarkin.) What fascinated me about this film was that while it was obviously a monster film, they never showed you the monster! You got glimpses here and there, but in general there wasn&amp;rsquo;t ever a &amp;ldquo;money shot&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years later I saw Alien. Easily one of the best sci fi films ever made, the monster spends more time in the shadows and comes off far scarier for it. I remember the first time I saw a complete shot of the alien in some magazine and I wished I had not seen it. My imagination had made it far larger and scarier in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blair Witch Project: Ok, so this is a love it or hate it type movie, and it got way too much marketing, but this film scared the living crap of me. 
&lt;li&gt;The Village: Really the beginning of Night&#39;s descent into crap-hood, and featuring what my wife calls the Giant Killer Badger - the early scenes by the woods were very well done. When one of the kids goes to the edge of the woods, and turns his back, I can literally feel my legs tensing in some subconscious attempt to get him to get the heck away.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0464141/&#34;&gt;El Orfanto&lt;/a&gt; (The Orphanage) - A well done ghost story with a grand total of one shot of gore, this one was simply incredible. My wife really enjoyed it as well.
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0097100/&#34;&gt;Communion&lt;/a&gt; - Supposedly a true story of alien contact, any film with Christopher Walken is worth watching in my opinion. It&#39;s been years since I&#39;ve seen this, but I remember being royally creeped out multiple times. One scene in particular has the main character simply sitting down in a room - and across the way an alien sticks his head out - slowly. 
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s all I can think of right now. Any other recommendations? Think high creep/low blood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Clone Wars - It didn&#39;t suck!</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2008/08/24/Review-Clone-Wars-It-didnt-suck</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 15:08:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2008/08/24/Review-Clone-Wars-It-didnt-suck</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/cfjedi/poster.png&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; style=&#34;margin-right:10px;margin-bottom:10px&#34;&gt; Yesterday I took my three kids to see the new Clone Wars movie. I knew it was coming to TV eventually, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t pass up the chance to see more Star Wars on the big screen. My boys are pretty big Star Wars fans themselves (gee, I wonder where they get that from) and my daughter, well, she loves her daddy so that was enough for her. The title of this blog entry is a bit of a joke. I am not one of those Star Wars fan who hate Lucas or thinks he is raping the franchise. I do think some parts of the prequels suck. But at the same time - I don&amp;rsquo;t see Jar Jar being any more worse than the Ewoks. (Although we do get to see an Ewok die though&amp;hellip;) I read quite a few negative reviews of the movie, but I went with an open mind and figured - at worse - my boys would absolutely love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out the movie really doesn&amp;rsquo;t suck! I had been &lt;b&gt;extremely&lt;/b&gt; pleased, surprised even, by the first Clone Wars series that came out a year or so ago. Some of the scenes in that series were easily as cool as any of the stuff in the both the prequel and classic series. (Especially the giant foot ship!) In my mind, this new series is even better. The pacing is a lot more intense, and I felt that the story comes off better then the first series. (To be honest though, seeing everything at once does tend to reinforce the storyline more than seeing a series by watching a few minutes at a time.) I found it kind of cool to see the Jedi bending over backwards to help Jabba. It was also nice to get a bit more detail about the war in general. I think this movie opens the door to a lot more material in the period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animation style is&amp;hellip; well interesting. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely different from the first series, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bit artsy, but I thought it was ok. The only character design I didn&amp;rsquo;t care for was Dooku. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t take my eyes off his super deformed nose. On the flip side, Ventress was awesome. Easily as cool as Darth Maul, she is a welcome addition to the Universe and I hope we can see more of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there was one thing I &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; didn&amp;rsquo;t care for - it was the Mardi Gras Hutt. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember his real name, but if you see the movie you will know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. His part in the story - fine. But his voice, design, etc, just annoyed the heck out of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br clear=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Mega Media Review</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2008/06/22/Sunday-Mega-Media-Review</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2008 08:06:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2008/06/22/Sunday-Mega-Media-Review</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to post a few quick reviews and as I&amp;rsquo;ve got nothing to do until I board my plane, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take the time and share some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Incredible Hulk - I saw this last night with some friends at CFUNITED. While not as good as Iron Man, it was pretty darn good. Yes - the CGI is very fake looking. There is no way you are going to make a 1-ton green monster look real. But - Edward Norton did a great job, the story was well done, and I loved the nods to the old show. Oh - and I won&amp;rsquo;t ruin the spoiler, but the entire movie was made cooler by one line uttered by the Hulk. We should also give credit to the movie company behind Iron Man for letting their actor appear in another company&amp;rsquo;s movie. Both may be Marvel properties, but still, that was pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sex and City - Ok, so this is trash, but I enjoyed the series when it was on TV. The movie was &lt;i&gt;way&lt;/i&gt; too long, but if you liked the series, then this simply adds a few more episodes to the run. I&amp;rsquo;d probably just rent it from Netflix or Blockbuster though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kung Fu Panda - Jack Black is the king. This is one of the best kid movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in a while. I thought the animation style was done well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Happening - Absolute, 100%, trash. I&amp;rsquo;ve given up on Night. Completely. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen better acting in high school. I&amp;rsquo;d rather push rusty, dull, smelly nails through my eyes, backwards, than watch this film again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Invasion - An older one - but I just saw it. Meh. Nicole Kidman is nice to look at, but outside of that, this is just one more remake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>