<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adoption on Raymond Camden</title>
    <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/categories/adoption/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adoption on Raymond Camden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 10:07:14 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.raymondcamden.com/categories/adoption/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>November is National Adoption Month</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/11/02/november-is-national-adoption-month-3</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 10:07:14 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/11/02/november-is-national-adoption-month-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year or so (although sometimes later than planned), I like to remind people that November is National Adoption Month. My wife and I have adopted six times over the past fifteen years. We adopted three times from South Korea and three times from China. It is an incredible experience - and &amp;ldquo;incredible&amp;rdquo; in every way possible. Joyous, scary, exciting, nerve-wracking, etc. My wife and I both advocate for adoption (both international and domestic) and &lt;strong&gt;highly&lt;/strong&gt; encourage people to look into if they are in any way interested. Here are just a few random links for more information and if you have any questions, just drop me a comment below. (And if it is something you would rather discuss in private, you can drop me an email too.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.childwelfare.gov/topics/adoption/nam/&#34;&gt;National Adoption Month&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationaladoptionday.org/&#34;&gt;National Adoption Day (November 21st)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://adoption.org/&#34;&gt;Adoption.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>self.getFamily().addOne().addOne()</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/11/01/selfgetFamilyaddOneaddOne</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 20:11:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/11/01/selfgetFamilyaddOneaddOne</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
As I&#39;ve mentioned almost every year, November is &#34;National Adoption Month.&#34; My wife and I have grown our family via adoption. It is an incredibly wonderful experience and one I&#39;d recommend to anyone. It isn&#39;t easy, but, nothing about being a parent is, right? If you&#39;ve ever considered adoption then this would be a great time to look deeper into the process. You can start at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adoption.com&#34;&gt;Adoption.com&lt;/a&gt; or check with your adoption agency. There are multiple different ways to adopt, or foster, and plenty of opportunities to help a child in need. My wife and I chose international adoption (South Korea and China), but you can adopt domestically as well of course. (And yes, people adopt American kids from outside the USA.) 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
You can probably guess what I&#39;m going to say next. A few weeks ago I mentioned I&#39;d be too busy to post for a while and then I dropped a few &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/10/23/Yesterday&#34;&gt;obvious&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/10/25/Beautiful&#34;&gt;hints&lt;/a&gt;. Yes - we adopted again. We flew to Guangzhou, China on October 17th. On the 20th we met our two new daughters. Yes, two. Because we&#39;re crazy. Just a bit. We have one new three year old and a twelve year old. Adopting an older child has its own special issues but it is something I&#39;ve felt we needed to do since we began adopting.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
We landed back in America yesterday morning and while we have a lot of work ahead of us, I don&#39;t think our family could be any better. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/IMAG0648(1).jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I apologize again for having to drop out of the ColdFusion conference and PhoneGap Day, but I think I had a pretty good excuse. ;)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Thanksgiving - and what I&#39;m thankful for...</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/11/28/Happy-Thanksgiving-and-what-Im-thankful-for</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 06:11:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/11/28/Happy-Thanksgiving-and-what-Im-thankful-for</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone. First off - for those who celebrate it, I hope today is a wonderful Thanksgiving for you. As I mentioned in my last blog post, I was working on a &amp;ldquo;project&amp;rdquo; for the past few weeks and was not able to blog. Now I&amp;rsquo;m back home and able to share some good news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/12.jpg&#34;  /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, November 14th, my wife and I boarded a flight to Beijing, China. We took off from Lafayette early in the morning (early enough for them to need to de-ice, in Louisiana, I still can&amp;rsquo;t believe that), connected in Houston, then San Francisco, and finally took off to the other side of the planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China is - incredible. In ways it reminds of something out of a science fiction movie. You know the country is full of people but you don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; know this. Trust me - you have no idea. I can still remember the sight of 8 or so apartment buildings being constructed at once. And then our car drove past them and I could see what appeared to be about 30-40 or so more past them. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about one &lt;i&gt;set&lt;/i&gt; of apartment buildings. It&amp;rsquo;s trite, but all I could think of was SimCity with a money cheat.   Remember the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sMXjtvMAFlI&#34;&gt;intro to Batman Beyond&lt;/a&gt; where the skyline of Gotham gradually reveals an entirely new skyline behind the original? That&amp;rsquo;s what it was like. Heck, even the factories were of an unimaginable size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is great beauty too. In Beijing we visited Tiananmen Square, the Forbidden City, and the Great Wall as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/32.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visiting these sites was truly awe inspiring. Again, you aren&amp;rsquo;t truly prepared for it until you are actually there. The Forbidden City was especially amazing. You enter it via multiple &amp;ldquo;Gates&amp;rdquo; (which are huge structures themselves) revealing layer after layer of the site. It seems to go forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/51.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left Beijing on Sunday and flew to Nanchang. That day we met our new daughter, Maisie. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to post any pictures because, well, this is public, but she is a healthy, precocious (i.e. naughty), four year old. This is our fourth adoption, and our first from China. This has been in the works for some time now, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to talk about until we got back home. Our family now is larger, more wonderful, and without sounding too sappy, I am full of joy at a level I cannot adequately describe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent a few days in Nanchang before eventually flying to Guangzhou. Guangzhou is where the American consulate is and where we did our final preparations. We spent a week there and got to see many sites, but really the time was spent just hanging out with our daughter so she could get used to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/6.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had originally planned to write a lot more, but honestly I&amp;rsquo;m just happy to be back home with my kids. I&amp;rsquo;ve got 700 or so photos to go through and there will be work with my daughter to help her learn English, get comfortable with her new home, but this will all come in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. You don&amp;rsquo;t know what fun is until a four year old fusses at you in Mandarin. Best - experience - ever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November is National Adoption Month</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/11/10/November-is-National-Adoption-Month</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 19:11:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/11/10/November-is-National-Adoption-Month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Every year I remind folks that November is National Adoption Month. My wife and I adopted all of our children from South Korea. It was a wonderful experience. If you&#39;ve ever considered adoption as an option for growing your family, now is a perfect time to reach out and find out more. You can hit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adoption.com&#34;&gt;Adoption.com&lt;/a&gt; as a starting point or feel free to ask me anything. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I watched this video today and thought it was particularly touching. It gives you a good look at how kids view adoption.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;601&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/I6h_RkZw9W8?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November is National Adoption Month</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2011/11/16/November-is-National-Adoption-Month</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2011 09:11:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2011/11/16/November-is-National-Adoption-Month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once again I&amp;rsquo;m late to remind folks, but November is National Adoption Month, and the 19th is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationaladoptionday.org/&#34;&gt;National Adoption Day&lt;/a&gt;. If you have every considered adoption, or even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s a great time to look into it. I assume most folks know this, but my own family was grown via adoption. My wife and I adopted three kids from South Korea over the past decade. It&amp;rsquo;s a process that is&amp;hellip; quite involved. But it&amp;rsquo;s doable. And the rewards are beyond description. I typically recommend folks check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adoption.org/&#34;&gt;Adoption.org&lt;/a&gt; as a starting point. You can also contact local adoption agencies for a meeting to discuss possibilities. I&amp;rsquo;m open to questions too - either here on the blog or privately via my contact form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/NationalAdoptionDay.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November is National Adoption Month</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2009/11/21/november-is-national-adoption-month-2</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 13:11:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2009/11/21/november-is-national-adoption-month-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year I promise to blog this on the 1st, and every year it gets away from me. Personally, I think Time is an evil thief who must be killed at the earliest convenience, but maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just me getting old. In case you weren&amp;rsquo;t aware, November is national adoption month. You can read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/presidential-proclamations-national-adoption-month&#34;&gt;presidential proclomation&lt;/a&gt; here if you are interested. I&amp;rsquo;ll also pass along this nice list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.childwelfare.gov/&#34;&gt;highlights&lt;/a&gt; for the month (notice the CFM extension - and yes - it is a Model-Glue site).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular readers know that my wife and I chose adoption as the way to grow our family. We have three beautiful kids from South Korea. Adoption is a very special, very emotional, and very wonderful thing. If you have any questions I&amp;rsquo;d highly encourage you to ask - either myself or someone local to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll leave you with two small pieces of advice when it comes to talking to families who have adopted. First - don&amp;rsquo;t ask about the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; parents. I hate to be PC, but this is one thing that really ticks me off, as it does most adoptive parents. Obviously the person raising the child is the real parent. It&amp;rsquo;s best to refer to the birth parents as the biological parents (or birth parents). Secondly - don&amp;rsquo;t ask something you aren&amp;rsquo;t willing to answer yourself. I&amp;rsquo;ve had folks ask how much I paid for my kids (yes, seriously, and to be clear, you pay for paperwork and handling, not children), ask if they are related, and ask if they knew they were adopted (gee, my kids aren&amp;rsquo;t blind, and I&amp;rsquo;m a bit pale compared to them ;). Just keep it in mind. Questions about processes, wait times, how to &lt;i&gt;manage&lt;/i&gt; costs, etc are fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously I speak just for myself and not all adoptive parents.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South Korea closing out international adoption</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2009/08/11/South-Korea-closing-out-international-adoption</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 15:08:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2009/08/11/South-Korea-closing-out-international-adoption</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So this is about as off topic as you can get, but I had to share. My wife sent the following article to me that I thought others may want to read as well: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rainbowkids.com/ArticleDisplay.aspx?id=664&#34;&gt;Korea Slowly Closes to Adoption&lt;/a&gt; (I&amp;rsquo;m linking to the plain print format as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require a login.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned adoption more than once here, but in case it isn&amp;rsquo;t really well known, my kids are all adopted, and all adopted from South Korea. My family is - in my mind anyway - a South Korean/American family. A mix. I love that. I love that my kids don&amp;rsquo;t look the same as my wife and I. I love that we are unique. But now I kind of feel like our type of family is coming to an end. Rationally, I can look at these changes as Koreans taking care of their own, which is good I suppose, but it feels like my entire type of family is coming to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how others feel about this - native Koreans, adoptees, etc. But I&amp;rsquo;m truly saddened by this, and feel pretty blessed that I was able to help create the family I have now. I hope South Korea can place &lt;b&gt;all&lt;/b&gt; those children waiting for families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t expect much comment on this - just wanted to share and hopefully give folks something to think about. I promise an on topic post next.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy November, Happy National Adoption Month</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2007/11/01/Happy-November-Happy-National-Adoption-Month</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 15:11:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2007/11/01/Happy-November-Happy-National-Adoption-Month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;November is national adoption month, which also includes the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationaladoptionday.org/2007/index.asp&#34;&gt;National Adoption Day&lt;/a&gt; on the 17th. My wife and I adopted three beautiful kids from South Korea and consider it to be the best decisions in our life. If you have ever considered adoption then this is a perfect time to start looking into it more. It is a long, and sometimes &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; difficult process, but hey, so is life too. Check out About.com&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://adoption.about.com/od/adopting/a/30daycalendar.htm&#34;&gt;list of ideas&lt;/a&gt; on how to celebrate the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And hey - you get your fingerprints sent to INTERPOL - how cool is that???&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helping orphans in Iraq</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2007/07/10/Helping-orphans-in-Iraq</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2007 12:07:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2007/07/10/Helping-orphans-in-Iraq</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched a pretty disturbing report last night on the state of orphans in Iraq. More information on the story may be found here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2007/07/09/eveningnews/main3035523.shtml&#34;&gt;The Orphan He Couldn&amp;rsquo;t Leave Behind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story details an American soldier who adopted an orphan from Iraq and is trying to help others. The state of the orphans there is incredibly bad. When my wife and I were adopting, one of the reasons we skipped over Russia was due to the state of the orphanages. What I saw on the news last night made Russia look like paradise. I would highly encourage folks to consider helping out as well. CBS has two links here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2007/06/19/fyi/main2949887.shtml&#34;&gt;How To Help The Baghdad Orphans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One link is just to hook you up with an agency trying to help the orphans while another link is specifically related to adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November is National Adoption Month</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2005/11/01/November-is-National-Adoption-Month</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 10:11:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2005/11/01/November-is-National-Adoption-Month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Normally I&amp;rsquo;d post this over at my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theadoptionnews.com&#34;&gt;adoption blog&lt;/a&gt;, but I wanted to make sure everyone knew that November is National Adoption Month. The National Adoption Day is November 19th, and more information may be found here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationaladoptionday.org&#34;&gt;http://www.nationaladoptionday.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog: The Adoption News</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2005/08/24/New-Blog-The-Adoption-News</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2005 19:08:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2005/08/24/New-Blog-The-Adoption-News</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As readers of this blog know, I&amp;rsquo;ve adopted three beautiful, wonderful, and of course perfect (ahem) children from South Korea. The adoption process is a wonderful, and trying process. I try to keep up to date on the latest adoption news even though our adoptions are complete (for now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t found a good resource to aggregate various adoption-related news items out there, so I figured, why not make my own. Check it out here at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theadoptionnews.com&#34;&gt;The Adoption News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is running BlogCFC and Galleon. Also the picture from purchased from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.istockphoto.com&#34;&gt;iStockPhoto.com&lt;/a&gt;, which despire my earlier &lt;a href=&#34;http://ray.camdenfamily.com/index.cfm/2005/8/24/Vile-Forms&#34;&gt;complaints&lt;/a&gt;, is a very nice and useful service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy \&#34;Gotcha\&#34; Day</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2005/05/17/EBD63A1F-DC7B-D8FE-F15910C5ADB20D86</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2005 15:05:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2005/05/17/EBD63A1F-DC7B-D8FE-F15910C5ADB20D86</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a totally unrelated note - today is the 3rd anniversary of my daughter&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Gotcha&amp;rdquo; day. That&amp;rsquo;s the day a child joins a family through adoption. Three years ago today a young, very small girl was placed in our arms&amp;hellip; screaming. (And she is still loud - I can&amp;rsquo;t wait till she is a teenager.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s Your Daddy?</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2005/01/03/3AF6D32B-9F3D-49FD-C37B9DC02223EE1B</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2005 15:01:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2005/01/03/3AF6D32B-9F3D-49FD-C37B9DC02223EE1B</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I hate it when folks in certain groups become whiny - always seeming to take offense at something that offends them when the context is not inflammatory or meant to offend. Sure, sometimes folks have legitimate concerns, but a lot of times I think folks just need to get over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I especially hate it when someone condemns a show/book/movie/etc without actually experiencing the media for itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said I&amp;rsquo;m going to turn into a big hypocrite and go against all of the above. Fox will soon be airing a new show called &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s Your Daddy?&amp;rdquo; The idea is that an adopted woman will have to guess who her birth father is amongst a group of men. I just don&amp;rsquo;t even know if I have the words to express how disgusting this is. As an adoptive father, I&amp;rsquo;m definitely biased, but I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine this being a healthy way to talk about adoption. Of course, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this is worse than the movie Elf, where the main character is said to be going on a trip to find his &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; parents. (Yes, we only take care of them for 18 years or so - but we aren&amp;rsquo;t the real parents.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy to see, however, that at least one station &lt;a href=&#34;http://story.news.yahoo.com/news?tmpl=story&amp;cid=529&amp;e=3&amp;u=/ap/20050103/ap_en_tv/who_s_your_daddy&#34;&gt;won&amp;rsquo;t be airing&lt;/a&gt; the show.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>