<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Video Games on Raymond Camden</title>
    <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/categories/video-games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video Games on Raymond Camden</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 10:25:47 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.raymondcamden.com/categories/video-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Media in 2015</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/28/favorite-media-in-2015</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 10:25:47 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/28/favorite-media-in-2015</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following up on my previous non-tech/just for fun posts (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/23/books-i-read-in-2015&#34;&gt;Books I Read in 2015&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/22/my-year&#34;&gt;My Year&lt;/a&gt;), here is my favorite media of 2015. This was originally going to be my favorite music of the year, but I figured I&amp;rsquo;d expand it a bit to cover movies and video games too. This is obviously a very personal list, but hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll get some ideas about things to watch/play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Favorite Music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is in no particular order, but here are the tracks I listened to a &lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt; this year. The first track, &amp;ldquo;Close Your Eyes&amp;rdquo;, is incredible. I first heard it on Sirius XMU and was just blown away. It sounds like a pop/rap/NIN mashup and is a great song to turn up real, real loud - just be sure the kids aren&amp;rsquo;t around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PkGwI7nGehA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of mashups, my favorite this year was a mix of NIN and Taylor Swift. The video is really well done too. Even better, my 5 year old just loves the hell out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DhvXST1Rc3g&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another surprise was the new Prodigy album - the first single was freaking awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/h1AaKBbNGkk&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently, this Grimes track has been on repeat for me as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Tv9YoYCKNoE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while not new, my favorite song from the past few years has been pretty consistent - &amp;ldquo;Wings&amp;rdquo; by HAERTS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yk52XHSpmF4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Movies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, the &lt;i&gt;big&lt;/i&gt; movie for me was - obviously - the Force Awakens. I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/18/review-star-wars-the-force-awakens&#34;&gt;reviewed&lt;/a&gt; it already. But what else impressed me this year? I thought both &amp;ldquo;Avengers 2&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Ant-Man&amp;rdquo; were great Marvel films. I liked how different they were. One was a huge scale/popcorn chomping film while the other was much smaller, personable, still with great action. And while I&amp;rsquo;m not specifically writing up a TV section, &amp;ldquo;Jessica Jones&amp;rdquo; was &lt;i&gt;damn&lt;/i&gt; good too. As an aside, Netflix is the best thing to happen to TV in a long time. From their own content to their documentary selection to even some of their &amp;ldquo;B&amp;rdquo; flicks, I feel like I could easily pay more for the service. Speaking of Marvel - don&amp;rsquo;t bother seeing the Fantastic Four film. It isn&amp;rsquo;t watchable even if you can see it for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Inside Out&amp;rdquo; was easily one of the best children&amp;rsquo;s movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen since &amp;ldquo;Up&amp;rdquo;. I loved &amp;ldquo;The Martian&amp;rdquo; and will be reading the book next year. &amp;ldquo;The Visit&amp;rdquo; proved to me that M.Night &lt;i&gt;may&lt;/i&gt; have a tiny bit of talent left (stress - &amp;ldquo;may&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was initially a bit disappointed by &amp;ldquo;Mad Max&amp;rdquo;, but after watching it a second time I appreciate it a bit more. I still feel like it was more a &amp;ldquo;Film set in the Mad Max universe&amp;rdquo; then a proper &amp;ldquo;Mad Max&amp;rdquo; film, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just being too picky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one film I&amp;rsquo;d like folks to consider, it is &amp;ldquo;Maggie&amp;rdquo;. This flew &lt;i&gt;way&lt;/i&gt; under the radar - I don&amp;rsquo;t think I saw it advertised once - but it is an incredibly well done zombie film. Outside of &amp;ldquo;The Walking Dead&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m really tired of zombies, but this is the best zombie film I&amp;rsquo;ve seen since &amp;ldquo;28 Days Later.&amp;rdquo; I highly recommend seeing &amp;ldquo;Maggie&amp;rdquo; as soon as you can. I never thought I&amp;rsquo;d see a zombie film that was slow and thoughtful - but this movie really pulls if off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2xSzwS_wK-0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and as for stuff I&amp;rsquo;m embarrassed to admit - my guilty pleasure recently is &amp;ldquo;The Royals.&amp;rdquo; It is pure and utter trash, but fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/t1XvUYvdr3s&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For next year, keep an eye out for &amp;ldquo;Colony&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of alien invasion stories, especially ones that are far removed from &amp;ldquo;Independence Day&amp;rdquo;, and this one looks fascinating so far. You can watch the first episode online now if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to wait. Of course, like most sci-fi shows with a &amp;ldquo;mystery&amp;rdquo;, you have to assume it will probably get cancelled before they resolve anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oRLW-qQLMQs&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Video Games&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I just checked, and apparently, I only reviewed 2 video games this year - Battlefront and Destiny. I liked them both, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d consider them great. I&amp;rsquo;m spending a &lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt; of time during this Christmas break playing Fallout 4, and I like it a lot too, but again, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;ll be thinking about it in a year&amp;rsquo;s time. As an example of what I mean - my eldest son recently borrowed my PS3 (the PS4 now rules my TV) so he could play &amp;ldquo;The Last of Us&amp;rdquo;, and I still tend to think of that game when I think about what makes a truly &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo; video game. (And if folks are curious, my all time favorite game was &amp;ldquo;A Mind Forever Voyaging&amp;rdquo;.) I guess the best I can say is that I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying the three games I mentioned and I recommend them, but nothing has blown me away this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will add that both Sony and Microsoft have deals where if you pay for a yearly multiplayer subscription, you get free games every month. While the quality goes up and down, there have been some really great freebies. So even if you don&amp;rsquo;t play online a lot, you should definitely consider subscribing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Destiny and Star Wars Battlefront</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/05/review-destiny-and-star-wars-battlefront</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 10:12:18 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/12/05/review-destiny-and-star-wars-battlefront</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t Sunday but here are two video game reviews for you. Next will be Fallout 4 which should be at home within the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Destiny: The Taken King&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;float:left;margin-right:10px&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=raymondcamden-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00ZJ20YQO&amp;asins=B00ZJ20YQO&amp;linkId=PFCLK7EPMIBKMXL7&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t planning on getting Destiny because every time I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up a MMORPG I end up not playing and then feeling guilty when I pay for a month&amp;rsquo;s usage that I didn&amp;rsquo;t - well - use. There&amp;rsquo;s no monthly fee for Destiny though and after seeing reviews of the Taken King DLC praising it for incredibly improving the game experience, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Destiny is a shooter with RPG elements. You&amp;rsquo;ve got 3 classes with 3 subclasses each. You&amp;rsquo;ve got equipment that adapts to different play styles and levels up as well. To be honest, it is more shooter than RPG, but that&amp;rsquo;s fine with me. Unlike a typical Call of Duty game where your character doesn&amp;rsquo;t change throughout the story, you really get a good feeling of progression as you go through the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is - unfortunately - a hot mess. There&amp;rsquo;s actually a good story about how the game&amp;rsquo;s story got so messy (&lt;a href=&#34;http://kotaku.com/the-messy-true-story-behind-the-making-of-destiny-1737556731&#34;&gt;The Messy, True Story Behind The Making Of Destiny&lt;/a&gt;), but to be honest, it didn&amp;rsquo;t really bug me too much. As I went through the various chapters, I figured out pretty early on that things weren&amp;rsquo;t going to make sense and I just went with it. There&amp;rsquo;s a wealth of online material in a &amp;lsquo;codex&amp;rsquo; that I could make time to read if I cared, but frankly I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be bothered. You&amp;rsquo;ve got - basically - a space opera with all kinds of weird names thrown at you with loads of depth that ends up making no sense because there&amp;rsquo;s never any context given to what you&amp;rsquo;re being told. It is a huge failure imo, but a testament to the game that I still enjoyed the heck out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is also a bit confusing if you&amp;rsquo;ve never played a MMORPG before. The idea of a central hub where you can get quests and deal with factions and earning reputation and all that made sense to me, but if you&amp;rsquo;ve never seen these things before you&amp;rsquo;re going to be pretty confused. Maybe Destiny can&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;fix&amp;rdquo; the story problems, but I think they could do more to make some of the &amp;lsquo;mechanics&amp;rsquo; of the game itself more familiar to players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue with the game is that because it is online only, there is no real concept of pause. Now - to be fair - this is true of all MMORPGs. But at least in Warcraft I could hop on a winged mount, lift myself above the ground, and essentially be untouchable while I take care of something. You can find quiet places in Destiny during a mission, but for the most part, once you start something you have to assume 20-40 minutes of play without the ability to pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said though, the game play is incredibly fun. It takes the shooter genre and really makes it much more interesting. Some of the battles were &lt;i&gt;amazing&lt;/i&gt;. On more than one occasion you have to solve a minor puzzle in terms of how in the heck you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to harm the boss. All while the boss is raining death upon you at the same time. These fights were some of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in shooters. Ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve finished the main story and am now in what would be called the &amp;ldquo;end game&amp;rdquo; content. Things here get a bit slower and the difficulty jumps a bit all of a sudden. I&amp;rsquo;m not quite as excited about the game now as it feels like you get a bit less reward per game session, but I&amp;rsquo;m definitely going to keep at it for a while longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only aspect I really didn&amp;rsquo;t care for is PVP. Maybe I didn&amp;rsquo;t dedicate enough time to it but every match I was in was an exercise in frustration. I did win a few matches, but never scored well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game has a cool mobile app companion as well as a web-based profile. Here&amp;rsquo;s my character - not the prettiest one in the world but she&amp;rsquo;s mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/shot12.png&#34; alt=&#34;shot1&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;349&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-7213&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Star Wars Battlefront&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;float:left;margin-right:10px&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=raymondcamden-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B016NZFGP4&amp;asins=B016NZFGP4&amp;linkId=ZK4HJ76UPQVI6DHA&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now for something completely different&amp;hellip; Star Wars Battlefront is another online only (well, &lt;i&gt;mostly&lt;/i&gt;) game focused on PVP. Unlike Destiny, there&amp;rsquo;s no story. The entire game is literally various different types of PVP matches with some training and &amp;lsquo;fend off waves of attacks&amp;rsquo; solo play as well. (It feels like I&amp;rsquo;m dismissing the offline/solo matches. They are fun. They just aren&amp;rsquo;t really the meat of the game.) But since most of us know the Star Wars story by heart, it isn&amp;rsquo;t something that bothers me. What makes me happiest of all is that the setting is entirely within the original series. While I certainly do not hate the Prequels, it seems like it has been a long time since we&amp;rsquo;ve had a good game in that setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game play is pretty vanilla for a shooter. Probably the biggest difference is the lack of ammo. Since your weapons are all energy based (except for rockets and grenades), you instead have to worry about overheating your gun. Another interesting aspect is the use of hero classes in some matches. Playing as Darth Vader or Luke is pretty cool and while powerful, the hero classes can be taken down with effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you&amp;rsquo;ve got an entire mode based in space ships as well. (Well, they are &amp;lsquo;space&amp;rsquo; ships but all matches are in atmosphere.) I enjoy the matches, but not as much as playing a trooper. One kind of weird issue with the vehicle matches is that you spawn well outside the main fighting and it can take up to 30 seconds to get to the fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s quite a few people complaining about how &amp;ldquo;shallow&amp;rdquo; the game is. Honestly, I don&amp;rsquo;t quite see it. There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://starwars.ea.com/starwars/battlefront/features/game-modes&#34;&gt;eight different PVP&lt;/a&gt; style matches and &lt;a href&#34;http://starwars.ea.com/starwars/battlefront/features/missions&#34;&gt;four different solo/local&lt;/a&gt; style matches. For basic PVP, you use 12 different maps that feel &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; different in terms of how they impact game play. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my time in one PVP game, Blast, and frankly it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel too shallow to me. Maybe you could make the argument that a game that skipped a single player story could have done a bit more, but I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had one complaint, it would be that leveling up seems like it doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite give you the rewards you expect based on the amount of time you spend. They really need to do a bit more here to reward you for the time you spend. There&amp;rsquo;s fifty different levels and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll have the time to actually hit the max level before my kids graduate. I&amp;rsquo;m comparing this to what I remember of the progression in Call of Duty and it definitely feels like Battlefront will need a heck of a lot more time to max out. You know what - the biggest thing I miss is ranks. Sergeant, Lieutenant, etc. I wish the game would add that. I know it sounds silly - but&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently level 21 with a bit over 13 hours play time. As you level up, the amount of experience required to gain a new level goes up, but the amount of experience you get from a game doesn&amp;rsquo;t really grow as much. Obviously better players will get more points, but there&amp;rsquo;s really a somewhat firm limit to how much you can reasonable expect. I really like this game so far, but the idea of hitting 50 seems like it may be too much of a commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side of all that complaining, I&amp;rsquo;m having a heck of a lot of fun. In general, I come in about the top half of my team and sometimes I even win some times. It was rare for me to do that well in Call of Duty. Another interesting aspect - according to my detailed stats I&amp;rsquo;ve only won about 38% of the time. That surprised me because it &lt;i&gt;felt&lt;/i&gt; like I was winning more. I think that&amp;rsquo;s a good sign. Even when I&amp;rsquo;m losing I&amp;rsquo;m still having fun, and that&amp;rsquo;s what matters, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can&amp;rsquo;t talk about this game without mentioning the graphics and sound. They are perfect. Seriously. Probably the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen in a video game and really go a long way towards capturing the spirit of Star Wars. Hell, even the menus are beautiful too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as I said - it is a fun game. Really fun. It has room to grow and I really hope they adjust level advancement, but I&amp;rsquo;m having a great time playing it. Probably the most I&amp;rsquo;ve had in a multiplayer environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Destiny, there is a companion site and mobile app for Battlefront, but the companion app also has a completely new game too - a simple turn based combat game. It isn&amp;rsquo;t incredible, but it&amp;rsquo;s free and gives you a few bonuses to your main game as well.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/File-Dec-05-10-09-50-AM.png&#34; alt=&#34;File Dec 05, 10 09 50 AM&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;1000&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-7216&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any way - that&amp;rsquo;s it for now. If you are playing either of these games, let me know in the comments below. As a reminder, if you click on the product links I get a small kick back when you purchase at Amazon. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some games to pick up</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/04/19/some-games-to-pick-up</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 20:08:12 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2015/04/19/some-games-to-pick-up</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As it is Sunday and I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in a hotel in a San Francisco killing time till dinner, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d catch folks up on the games I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing recently. There&amp;rsquo;s three in particular that are somewhat related so I thought why not share with my readers. These are in no more particular order than whatever comes to mind first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Heroes Generations&lt;/h4&gt;
The first is probably the quickest to pick up and great for a quick casual game, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.herogenerations.com/&#34;&gt;Hero Generations&lt;/a&gt;. Hero Generations (HG) is a very interesting concept. You play a fairly stereotypical RPG hero, but every move in the game equals one year of your life. The &amp;ldquo;generations&amp;rdquo; aspect comes in in regards to how you make your game last longer - by finding a mate and having a child. As you play, you gain traits that may or may not pass on to your offspring. This makes a typical &amp;ldquo;Kill the Big Ass Dragon&amp;rdquo; quest much more interesting than normal. You actually find yourself planning for your grandchild, or great grandchild, to be prepared to attack the beast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further making the game unique is that it has a &amp;ldquo;sim&amp;rdquo; aspect to it. The towns you encounter can be improved with things that bring both money and strength (the primary combat trait) to your character. The improvements you add now will be appreciated by your children in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make things even more interesting, the game has no save slots (well, it saves your state) and death is permanent. In my first game my lineage died out when I simply didn&amp;rsquo;t return to a town in time to marry and have a child. The game has a great casual yet intense mix to it and I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying it. The game is rather cheap too ($15).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9G7E8t5oLIs?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;City: Skylines&lt;/h4&gt;
I spent &lt;i&gt;many&lt;/i&gt; hours playing SimCity (cracked copies at that) at my university&amp;rsquo;s computer lab back in the 90s. I&amp;rsquo;ve played pretty much every iteration of it except for the last. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t so much bothered by the online requirement (Diablo 3 has that and I play the &lt;i&gt;hell&lt;/i&gt; out of that), but the game just kinda rubbed me the wrong way. If I remember right, it had forced connections to other cities and I just didn&amp;rsquo;t care for that. I wanted my sandbox to be&amp;hellip; well&amp;hellip; my sandbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I heard about &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/255710/&#34;&gt;City: Skylines&lt;/a&gt; and gave it a look. The first thing I noticed was that it was freaking beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/cs2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/cs2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cs2&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;422&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-6026&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/cs3.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/cs3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cs3&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-6027&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/cs.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/cs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cs&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-6028&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I picked it up and immediately felt like I was playing the good old SimCity I remembered from the past. The game play works well, but with obvious differences from classic SimCity. It seems like police and fire coverage don&amp;rsquo;t matter quite as much, and health seems to be way more critical to infrastructure. Sometimes it can be frustrating (I&amp;rsquo;ve entered stages where dead bodies pile up in homes no matter how many cemeteries I build), but mostly in a good way. Even better, it has a built in cheat mode, which I really appreciate in my sim games. Sometimes I just want to build and not worry about reality. ;) Like Heroes, this game is rather cheap too - currently 29.99 on &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/255710/&#34;&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Beyond Earth&lt;/h4&gt;
Or more accurately, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.civilization.com/en/games/civilization-beyond-earth/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization: Beyond Earth&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, is yet another sim but this time in the Civilization family. The last time I pulled an all nighter for a game was for Civilization - again - back in college - and again - playing cracked copies at my university. This game is - for all intents and purposes - the spiritual successor to Alpha Centauri, which was basically a sci fi version of Civ. I loved the game and so far I love this game too. Great graphics, interesting game play (like AC, the planet itself can be an adversary), and a good tech tree that actually makes sense for an advanced civilization. (It works more like a tree going in all directions than the more &amp;lsquo;directed&amp;rsquo; ones used in the other games.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an amazing amount of detail/story/etc to immerse yourself in to make the sim even more engrossing and out of the three games I listed today this is probably the most difficult and time consuming, so keep that in mind before you purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S0Jx6GVxuPQ?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday OT - Wolfenstein: The New Order</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/07/27/Sunday-OT-Wolfenstein-The-New-Order</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 09:07:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/07/27/Sunday-OT-Wolfenstein-The-New-Order</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&#39;ve been a fan of the Wolfenstein series for quite some time, and when I say &#34;quite some time&#34;, I&#39;m talking a &lt;i&gt;long time&lt;/i&gt;. I remember playing the original Wolfenstein, back before it got fancy with 3D:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/CastleWolfensteinC64.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Because of my long history with the game, I was really looking forward to trying the latest incarnation, and especially interested in seeing how a FPS performed on the PS4. I was not disappointed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Graphically and gameplay wise, the game is fun as hell. It has great balance, with only a few areas being out of sync difficulty wise with the others, and I found myself going to Google only for the very last boss battle. (And frankly, if I had just freaking looked up, it would have been pretty obvious what I needed to do.) The play is a &lt;i&gt;bit&lt;/i&gt; similar to Gears of War in terms of making wise use of cover, and there is a stealth element present as well. But like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/7/6/Sunday-OT--Video-Game-Reviews&#34;&gt;Dishonored&lt;/a&gt;, it is somewhat optional. If you feel like being stealthy you can be, but if you want to run in guns blazing, that&#39;s an option as well. Even though I stuck to a few main guns, the variety available and the upgrades made the selection fun. I&#39;m still not quite sure how they got a rocket launcher on an assault rifle, but I&#39;m perfectly fine just accepting that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The story is what really sold me though. I am a &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt; Alt-History fan, and while &#34;The Nazis won&#34; is kind of a trite example of the genre, in the game it works &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; well, especially mixed in with the sci-fi elements. As you play you come across various newspaper clippings and other items that give you a look at the history of the game and I made sure to read each and every one.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/wolfenstein-the-new-order.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Probably the only negative I can think of is that there is no multiplayer, but honestly, I don&#39;t do much multiplayer nowadays anyway so it doesn&#39;t bother me much. It is good to see a game focused on single player for once! The game lasted about twenty hours for me, which is a good long time, and there is actually a valid reason to replay the entire game (more than just - &#34;find all the hidden crap&#34;). I won&#39;t say why as it is somewhat of a spoiler, but I&#39;ve already started my second play through. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sound good? Buy it via the link below and I get like a dollar or so that I&#39;ll put to my next video game.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=raymondcamden-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00DHF39KS&amp;asins=B00DHF39KS&amp;linkId=YBJZG64A2F3K24MZ&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday OT - Video Game Reviews</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/07/06/Sunday-OT-Video-Game-Reviews</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 12:07:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2014/07/06/Sunday-OT-Video-Game-Reviews</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
It has been a while since I posted a video game review so today I&#39;m going to make up for that by posting not one, but three. Enjoy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;float:left;margin-right:10px&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=raymondcamden-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00BGAA0SU&amp;asins=B00BGAA0SU&amp;linkId=LFBSQ5F6PDXZY5UL&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

First up is Infamous Second Son for the PlayStation 4. I wasn&#39;t planning on getting &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; of the new consoles. None of them really seemed all that appealing to be honest. But I got a surprise gift of some AMEX gift checks and thought I&#39;d give the PS4 a try. I had a PS3 but honestly didn&#39;t play it much. Not that I didn&#39;t like it, but I only had a few games for it. The games I did have I enjoyed quite a bit. The new XBox was more expensive and had features I didn&#39;t quite care about. The PS4 was cheaper and seemed like a better fit, so I took the plunge. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Outside of the UI being a bit weird to me as I&#39;m more used to the 360, I really like the console. Once I got over how awkward the UI seemed and figured out how the PS does things, it felt more natural and streamlined than the 360. The first game I picked up was Second Son, an open world game set in Seattle. To me, there are two types of open world game. The simple, more directed ones, like Saints Row, and the more complex, deep games like GTA. In general, I prefer the simpler type and Second Son really matched that well. The graphics are great, but not some huge leap over the 360. If I had to peg it I&#39;d say it is about 50% better. (To be clear, I&#39;m talking about 50% better than &#39;top of the line&#39; 360 games.) I enjoyed the chaotic nature of the game and the story was fun. The powers you pick up over the course of the game are cool and I&#39;m pretty happy I picked this up first.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br clear=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;float:left;margin-right:10px&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=raymondcamden-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00BI83EVU&amp;asins=B00BI83EVU&amp;linkId=N5RCVXPODQXAALZM&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
Conversely, Watch Dogs was a very frustrating game. It&#39;s definitely more the GTA model. My introduction to the game was incredibly confusing. Time and time again I&#39;d fail something because I did something wrong without even knowing what I was doing &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; wrong. Like GTA, there&#39;s about 200 different activities you can do as opposed to playing the main missions and I find that distracting as hell. Maybe it&#39;s the OCD in me but I see all these minigames and feel like if I don&#39;t do them, I&#39;m somehow missing out on something important. I&#39;m not... but it&#39;s a hard feeling to shake.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; keep at it, and eventually the frustration went away. The story is very well done, certainly better than Second Son, and at least some of the minigame distractions are pretty fun. In particular, Spider Tank was so incredible I wish I could have purchased it separately. I discovered that the main missions were pretty simple and the story got me hooked enough to play through the entire game. In the end, it was worthwhile, and I&#39;d probably recommend it over Second Son, just be prepared to have a rough start of it and try to be patient.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I don&#39;t want to spoil it, but there is one mission towards the end that is awesome as hell, mainly because of the music they play in the background. When you get to it, you will know what I mean. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br clear=&#34;left&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;float:left;margin-right:10px&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=tf_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=raymondcamden-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B005C2D2MO&amp;asins=B005C2D2MO&amp;linkId=2IOCFNKAKVZNYE4H&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=false&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally a 360 game - Dishonored. This was a gift from someone, and if you are that person, please let me know. It arrived while I was out of town and my wife didn&amp;rsquo;t keep the receipt. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about this game and I don&amp;rsquo;t even remember when I added it to my wish list, but what a surprise. The setting is incredible - a mishmash of magic and steam punk set in a vaguely European industrial revolution setting. You play as an assassin, but can choose when and where to apply stealth. I typically suck at stealth games so I&amp;rsquo;m glad Dishonored made it optional. Everything about this game just really worked well for me - the setting, the gameplay, the story. I definitely recommend it and if this is the last 360 game I play, I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to end on such a high note.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br clear=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday OT: The Last of Us</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/12/22/Sunday-OT-The-Last-of-Us</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 11:12:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/12/22/Sunday-OT-The-Last-of-Us</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I&#39;ve had a PS3 now for... I think almost two years. In that time though I don&#39;t think I&#39;ve played one complete game. It&#39;s not that I disliked the PS3, but the games I cared for were on XBox as well and I just never really felt compelled to pick anything up specifically for the console. I did use it for blu rays, but now I&#39;m moving exclusively to iTunes for movie purchases so even that was a use case that was going away for me. With all that said, I felt a bit under-motivated lately when it came to video games. I had played the new Battlefield and COD recently, but I just wasn&#39;t excited about anything in particular the last few fews. (I know, totally a first world problem, right?)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
With all that being said, after recently helping someone out with a technical problem, I asked him to pick up &#34;The Last of Us&#34; from my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/o/registry/2TCL1D08EZEYE&#34;&gt;wish list&lt;/a&gt; when he asked how he could say thanks. I had heard good things about it and with it being a PS3 exclusive I thought it might be a good opportunity to actually &lt;i&gt;play&lt;/i&gt; a game on the console.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/vs1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Going into it, all I knew was that it was a good game, and a zombie game. I suppose, technically, you could call it a zombie game, but that&#39;s pretty far from the truth. The game is set about 20 or so years after an outbreak. The world isn&#39;t totally destroyed - the military still has safe zones to try to protect people from what are called the Infected, but most of the country is pretty bad off. You play the role of a man who has suffered great loss, but has managed to make a life for himself in the new world. The game revolves around you escorting a young girl to a safe location across the country.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The visuals in the game are incredible. This is an America that has gone wild over the past few decades. Wildlife has taken over the cities and buildings are crumbling down. More than once I found myself just looking around at the environment and appreciating the level of detail that went into the game.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/vs2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Of course, it wouldn&#39;t be much of a game without a bit of action. You find yourself fighting not only the Infected but humans as well. Combat is very well done. In a way it is a bit like Gears of War - there are &#34;encounters&#34; where once you&#39;ve cleared out a zone you know it is safe to proceed. These encounters also restart if you die. The fights are brutal. Seriously brutal. I saw some deaths that were pretty damn shocking in terms of the level of violence. There&#39;s a great mix of strategy and stealth here that works out well. Typically I&#39;m more of a &#34;run and gun&#34; type guy but I really enjoyed the combat. I had some difficulties with the controls at first, but I chalk that up more to me just not being familiar with the PS3 controller.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But above all this is the story. From beginning to end the story is gripping, dramatic, and best of all - unique. This is so far away from a &#34;zombie story&#34; that you should really just forget that aspect of it at all. The ending, especially, was incredibly well done. I was asked by a friend if I thought it was better than the ending to &#34;Bioshock Infinite&#34;, and I think it may be. (See my note at the end.) I don&#39;t want to give anything away, but the ending - in tone - is completely opposite of what you get in most games.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
One more small little thing I liked. At one point I got stuck. I was in a flooded basement of an abandoned building and was lost as to where to go. After a few minutes I was considering just giving up for the night and trying again the next day when all of a sudden the game took pity on me and told me exactly where to go. This happened a few times and frankly I&#39;m happy the game took pity on me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Next up for me is Uncharted 2. Before I wrap up what should be me last video game post of the year, I have to say that this was probably the best year in gaming I&#39;ve seen. Between &#34;Bioshock Infinite&#34;, &#34;The Last of Us&#34;, and the new &#34;Tomb Raider&#34;, I&#39;m really impressed with how deep, unique, and just how strong the medium is becoming. I hope the trend continues for next year.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?t=raymondcamden-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=B007CM0K86&amp;nou=1&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_top&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;bc1=000000&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sunday OT: My Favorite Video Game Commercials</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/11/10/The-Sunday-OT-My-Favorite-Video-Game-Commercials</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 08:11:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/11/10/The-Sunday-OT-My-Favorite-Video-Game-Commercials</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
As I&#39;m up too early this Sunday, I thought it was an appropriate time for another Sunday OT post. Earlier this week I was thinking about my favorite video game commercials so I thought I&#39;d share a few. As always, feel free to disagree and suggest your own. (But I&#39;m right - don&#39;t forget.) So far I&#39;m pretty unimpressed with what I&#39;ve seen for the XBox One and I don&#39;t even remember if I&#39;ve seen a PS4 commercial.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Let&#39;s start with one of my favorite - the Gears of War &#34;Mad World&#34; commercial. This was so unexpected for me and I can remember thinking at the time that I couldn&#39;t believe Microsoft would approve it. Gears of War is a great series, although I didn&#39;t get around to playing Judgement. If you really like the song, you can hear the entire thing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4N3N1MlvVc4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;601&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/ccWrbGEFgI8?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Next up is one that is so bat shit insane I can&#39;t believe it got approved as well. Sony had quite a few off the wall commercials, but this one pushes the limit. I suppose it succeeded in that I still remember it nearly twenty years later, but I can&#39;t see a parent watching this and thinking, &#34;Yeah, I&#39;ll go buy my kid a PS2!&#34;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Astj-sK-9Sk?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Next up is the slightly NSWF (audio) commercial for Battlefield 3. This was the second Battlefield game I picked up and the one that got me hooked to the series. Unfortunately 4 fell flat for me a bit (I&#39;m going to review it once I finish COD), but I absolutely love the imagery of this commercial.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/coOHjF4_apI?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
As for funny commercials, the &#34;Kevin Butler&#34; series for Sony was incredible. I wanted to pick just one but I found this 8 minute montage of all his commercials and just sat through the entire thing. I can&#39;t do that for TED videos so that just tells you how great this campaign was. (Actually, this is not &lt;i&gt;every&lt;/i&gt; commercial as I just remembered a few not in this collection.) Jerry Lambert (the actor behind Kevin Butler) is now in a Wendy&#39;s commercial which is just plain sad.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;601&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/ukgISn3P2nQ?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
And finally - my number one - most favorite video game commercial of all time - Dead Island. The game was nowhere near as emotional as this commercial (see my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/index.cfm/2011/10/23/Review-Dead-Island&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt;) but that doesn&#39;t make me like this commercial any less. The music, the shots, the emotional aspect of using a child, and the way it plays with time just makes this commercial brilliant. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;601&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/b0AAtOEyb3g?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday OT: Best 2600 Video Ever</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/08/11/Sunday-OT-Best-2600-Video-Ever</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 11:08:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/08/11/Sunday-OT-Best-2600-Video-Ever</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As someone who grew up with a 2600, I can say this is the best video on the system ever. I love the River Raid segment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;601&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/7CUppYmq-FQ?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way - that joystick? It hurt like hell after an hour or so of play.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Sunday morning mega-video game review</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/06/16/another-sunday-morning-megavideo-game-review</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 10:06:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/06/16/another-sunday-morning-megavideo-game-review</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I reviewed a video game on this blog so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d use today to catch you guys up with what I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing the last few months. As always, comments are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.comm/e/cm?t=raymondcamden-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=B00886WO5W&amp;nou=1&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_top&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;bc1=000000&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;float:left;margin-right:10px;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Dead Island: Riptide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reviewed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/index.cfm/2011/10/23/Review-Dead-Island&#34;&gt;Dead Island&lt;/a&gt; nearly two years ago, and it is stands out as my favorite zombie game ever. I had high hopes for this update but was rather disappointed to discover that it was nothing more than a packaged up DLC. Turns out other reviewers noted the same thing. It certainly starts off like a sequel - pretty much picking up mere minutes after the finish of the previous game - but the actual gameplay is nearly identical to the previous game. That bugged me at first, but, honestly, I let go of that and just tried to enjoy myself. I remembered how frightening some of the situations could be in the original and the same applied here. I remember how fun it was to attack zombies and the same applied here. As I&amp;rsquo;ve said, I&amp;rsquo;m not a gore person, but there is something just plan fun about taking a katana to a zombie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve finished this game, and I enjoyed it, but I&amp;rsquo;d definitely &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; pick it up while it is still full priced. (I just checked my Amazon link and I see it is 30 dollars now. To me, that&amp;rsquo;s on the edge. If you really enjoyed the first game than go ahead and jump.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way - I wonder if I&amp;rsquo;m the only one who encountered the &amp;ldquo;ship bug&amp;rdquo;. I had been playing for roughly five minutes when a wave pushed me into a room with no exits. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I saw a bug like that in a video game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/di1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/di2.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?t=raymondcamden-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=B005THAX5Q&amp;nou=1&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_top&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;bc1=000000&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;float:left;margin-right:10px&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Aliens: Colonial Marines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really torn about this one. Let me start by saying that I&amp;rsquo;m only about 20% through this game and - obviously - my opinion may change by the end. I went into this game with low expectations. The reviews were not good. But - I love the Aliens franchise. I&amp;rsquo;ve watched every movie, and while the quality goes downhill rather quickly in 3 and 4, I still will watch them and enjoy parts of them. I can remember watching Alien when I was too young, and since that time they have continued to scare the crap out of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thoughts going into this game were simple - as long as the game was barely decent, let&amp;rsquo;s say &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo; level, then being in the Aliens mythos would be enough for me. Did that work out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the first thing you notice when playing is how horrible the graphics are. I mean - my god. The graphics are so bad you almost want to congratulate the developers. They had to work &lt;i&gt;hard&lt;/i&gt; to ship a game with an engine that looks - I kid you not - like a 10 year old game. Way back in 2011 I reviewed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/index.cfm/2011/3/27/Review-Homefront-and-Bad-Company-2&#34;&gt;Homefront&lt;/a&gt;. This was another game with a bad graphics engine. But to me - the story and other aspects more than made up for it. Let me be clear. Aliens:CM makes Homefront look like freaking Crysis. As others have noted - many screenshots of the game were released before the game and not one of them come close to the actual final product. Here is a great image which just about sums it up. (Credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://furiousfanboys.com/2013/02/aliens-colonial-marines-summed-up-in-one-image/&#34;&gt;http://furiousfanboys.com/2013/02/aliens-colonial-marines-summed-up-in-one-image/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/AliensColonialCrap.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s the controller. I can pretty much deal with any controller setup, but something about this game&amp;rsquo;s design just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work out well for me. Mainly it is the melee attack. I accidentally trigger it in just about every encounter I have. I&amp;rsquo;ve died multiple times when I swung my weapon instead of actually firing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh - and then there&amp;rsquo;s the difficulty. I can generally play more FPS games at medium level. Not this one. With large gaps between checkpoints I had to &amp;lsquo;give up&amp;rsquo; a game I was 2 hours in and restart back at the beginning on the lowest difficulty level. It is insanely hard and unforgiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But&amp;hellip; there is something to this game that keeps bringing me back. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the sound of the pulse rifle. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the sound of the range finder and memories of the Aliens movie. You have all the parts here to a potential epic game. Combat, even with frustrating controls and difficulty works &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; well at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me give you an example. You&amp;rsquo;re on a ledge walking along a wall when you see a xenomorph headed your way. You&amp;rsquo;re using a shotgun so you know you need to wait till it is practically kissing you before you can pull the trigger. You watch as it races towards you when 30 feet away the fricker decides to stop walking on the ledge and crawl - like a bug - under the damn thing. That - is - freaky. You panic. You start jumping around looking in every direction. You know that if it sneaks up behind you and gets one hit in you&amp;rsquo;re probably dead. (Which - while frustrating - is probably more realistic.) Sure, you can find Youtube videos of the enemy AI doing stupid things, but when it works, it works very well in terms of ramping up the suspense levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the game is somewhat of a failure - but I&amp;rsquo;m going to finish it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?t=raymondcamden-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=B00CBUC38Y&amp;nou=1&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_top&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;bc1=000000&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;float:left;margin-right:10px&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Injustice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a weird relationship with fighting games. I enjoy them - but only for a short time. Mostly it is due to the fact that my memory is crap. I can never remember than 10+ button combinations for various moves. My fighting strategy then comes down to lucky button mashing combos and just going crazy. I dig that - but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make for a very deep experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;m having a hell of a fun time with Injustice. If you forget for a moment that Batman could stand a chance against Superman and just go with the whole willful suspension of belief thing - it is incredibly fun. The most fun - of course - are the super moves. These are 15-second long attacks that are so over the top they don&amp;rsquo;t even make sense. For example, check out the Joker&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;601&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/eqkEi0DNm1Y?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My son and I both died laughing watching this. I had to pause the game. Not every one works well, but when it does, it stands up to multiple viewings even.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently about 80% through with the story and I really dig it. The game gives you a good reason for super heroes to be fighting each other. (I&amp;rsquo;ll point out that the comic series made for the game is &lt;b&gt;damn&lt;/b&gt; good. Very surprising for a game time-in.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of all three games I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in this blog entry, this is the one I&amp;rsquo;d recommend the most.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday OT Post: Tomb Raider</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/03/24/sunday-ot-post-tomb-raider</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 11:03:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2013/03/24/sunday-ot-post-tomb-raider</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a gamer for a long time (Atari 2600 anyone?) but I&amp;rsquo;ve never played Tomb Raider. For a series that has been around for as long as it has, I&amp;rsquo;ve avoided it (outside of trying a demo once) for two reasons. First, the puzzles always seemed to be a bit too complex. Second, I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of games that require absolute precise actions. I had a copy of Assassin&amp;rsquo;s Creed a few years back and I kid you not - after 30 minutes I popped it out and never played it again. (I ended up giving it to someone else though so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t wasted.) I like my action games to be more &amp;ldquo;run and dumb&amp;rdquo; since I&amp;rsquo;ve got enough stress in my life without video games adding to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I heard &lt;a href=&#34;http://remotesynthesis.com/&#34;&gt;Brian Rinaldi&lt;/a&gt; praise the game I thought - maybe it was time to check it out. I also asked him specifically about how &amp;ldquo;delicate&amp;rdquo; the game play was and he assured me it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too tough. A reader graciously sent me a copy via my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/o/registry/2TCL1D08EZEYE&#34;&gt;Amazon wishlist&lt;/a&gt; a week or so ago and I pretty much played it every free moment I had since then. On Friday I finished it, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be playing it more to get to 100% - just to give you an idea of how enjoyable it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right from the beginning you can see that the game is beautiful. Every scene, every area, everything is just damn beautiful. I&amp;rsquo;d definitely place it up there with Skyrim in terms of graphical quality, maybe even a bit higher as I think there was more variety in Tomb Raider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/1e76c7fb96f65f15_999_large.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game play is - as Brian told me - not difficult at all. Of course, I played on the lowest difficulty, but I found almost every jump/grab/etc to be somewhat easy to do. At the same time, your stomach tends to clench up as you see yourself jumping across a chasm. I typically only screwed up these parts of the game when I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay attention. It was rare for me to miss a jump, but as I said, it still felt pretty damn intense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/tr_jump.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not having played Tomb Raider in the past, I don&amp;rsquo;t know how much combat was a part of the game, but I really enjoyed the fighting. It was visceral, intense, and bloody. The enemy AI was a disappointment at times. I mean, on one hand they correctly handle the fact that if you kill a guy in front of another, he will react. Cool. On the other hand, if you killed someone ten feet away and his buddy didn&amp;rsquo;t notice, he could literally turn around, see the corpse, and just carry on as normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/tr_stalk.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What surprised me was the lack of puzzle solving. As you play, you run across tombs that are clearly marked &lt;b&gt;optional&lt;/b&gt;. If you choose to skip these, you miss nothing, outside of the resultant experience points. I was surprised they didn&amp;rsquo;t require some puzzle solving as I had always heard that was a big part of the Tomb Raider genre. I always did them when the opportunity arose and found them to be just about the right level of difficulty. None required precision reflexes and mentally they were slightly challenging but not stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of this game though is the story. This is - easily - one of the best written games I&amp;rsquo;ve ever played. As this is meant to be an origin story, Lara does not start off as a bad ass. She starts weak, ignorant, and scared. As she is pushed around, shot at, and almost killed multiple times, she grows, quickly, into a hero. The progression is well done and really connects you to the character. There is a scene towards the end where Lara passes by a mirror and is shocked by how much she is changed. It is a stark, quiet moment in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a strong &amp;ldquo;Lost&amp;rdquo; vibe to the game. The Island is mysterious and seems to have a life of its own. Like the TV show, there is a &lt;i&gt;long&lt;/i&gt; history here with ruins/remains of various groups. I kept expecting to see a Dharma logo hidden away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I definitely recommend it, and if you pick it up from the link below I get a little kick back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_top&amp;bc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;nou=1&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;fc1=000000&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;t=raymondcamden-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;m=amazon&amp;f=ifr&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;asins=B004FSE52C&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Mega Video Game Review</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/11/25/sunday-mega-video-game-review</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 14:11:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/11/25/sunday-mega-video-game-review</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the holiday weekend I binged a bit. Certainly on food and good beer, but mostly on video games. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on kind of a XBox rejection lately. Ever since I finished Red Dead Redemption (amazing game by the way), I&amp;rsquo;ve not found anything interesting enough to actually turn on the console. But over the past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky to get not one, but three really good games. What follows are my thoughts on each, and as always, I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to hear what my readers think. (As a reminder, the product links are affiliate links. If you purchase through them, I get a little kick back.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Forza Horizon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I got my XBox 360, my primary console was the PS2. I owned an original XBox, but didn&amp;rsquo;t play many games on it. One of my favorite games for the PS2 was Gran Turismo. To be honest, before Gran Turismo, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know there were other forms of racing outside of NASCAR. I had heard of F1, but it never really entered my mind. Thirty minutes into Gran Turismo and I was hooked. And when I discovered rally racing? Holy crap. How could anyone watch NASCAR after that? (And to be fair - I&amp;rsquo;ve seen grown to appreciate NASCAR quite a bit!) Switching to the 360 meant I had to leave GT behind, but I was encouraged enough by reviews of Forza to give a try. I loved it. In fact, I thought it did things better than Gran Turismo. I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten the most recent GT for my PS3, but it simply didn&amp;rsquo;t excite me as much as Forza did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I heard that the newest Forza was doing the &amp;ldquo;open world&amp;rdquo; thing, I was a bit worried. In terms of &amp;ldquo;serious&amp;rdquo; racing, I definitely had my favorite games. In terms of &amp;ldquo;arcade&amp;rdquo; racing, I was a huge Burnout fan. When Burnout went open world, I was pretty disappointed with the result. As an example of where I thought they failed, imagine this. You spend a few minutes driving to a race. You begin the race and are kicking ass when all of a sudden you make a wrong turn. Since the race is in the &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo;, that&amp;rsquo;s actually pretty easy to do. With one mistake you&amp;rsquo;ve ruined your chances of winning or even getting a decent place. And here comes the kicker - no restart. From what I remember, the developers said they felt race restarts made the game unrealistic (because racing in a city at 100+ MPH is realistic) and they intentionally left the feature out. To me, this just made the game frustrating. Pretty much every time this happened I simply gave up on the race and did something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as you can imagine&amp;hellip; I was worried. But luckily I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to be. Forza Horizon is an incredibly fun game. So fun that even the task of driving to events is made fun. Every bit of driving you do in the game is full of opportunities. While exploring you can earn popularity points which increases your rank among other racers. You can find hidden items that reduce your part costs. You can challenge random racers for an on the spot competition. You can get records with speed cameras. And again - this is all non-event stuff. The events are pretty damn fun too. You&amp;rsquo;ve got standard lap races, point to point races, &amp;ldquo;illegal&amp;rdquo; street racing, even exhibition events that have you racing against air planes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the game&amp;rsquo;s difficulty to be a bit odd at times. I&amp;rsquo;d do races that were just the right level of challenge, and then do a supposedly &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; race against a computer opponent and find myself smoked quite soundly. Races are typically divided by classes of cars, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have a MINI Cooper going against a 500HP+ Dodge Viper. In most games, if I tuned my car to the very tip top of the class, I found the races easy to win, but in Horizon, even at the max for the level it was pretty hard to win. To be honest, I ended up setting the difficulty down to easy and that made things a bit more simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The graphics are top notch as well as the sound track, but after playing for 10 hours or so you will hear the same tracks. (Yeah, I can&amp;rsquo;t really fault them for that.) I&amp;rsquo;d use this opportunity to once again point out how sad it is that video games have better music than terrestrial radio, but, yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m old, get off my lawn, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over all - this is definitely my favorite Forza yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?t=raymondcamden-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=B0050SYDEQ&amp;nou=1&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_top&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;bc1=000000&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Black Ops 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is a bit of a mixed bag for me so far. I really enjoyed BO1 because of its historical nature. Sure, Modern Warfare is, well, modern, but I actually preferred the missions in BO. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s more my age than anything else, but it just felt cooler. BO2 continues this trend, but mixes in missions set in the future as well. I believe I&amp;rsquo;m about 20% through the single player campaign and so far the modern missions aren&amp;rsquo;t really that exciting to me. The historical ones still kick ass though. The mission in Afghanistan was especially cool. I kept waiting for Sly or Arnie to show up as a co-star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent more time in multi-player though and I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying it. MP in BO2 isn&amp;rsquo;t majorly different then the last few COD games. This is an incremental update rather than a huge change. But the changes that were made are pretty damn smart. As an example - your class has a certain number of things it can select. This includes weapons, attachments, and perks. You can imagine it like an old school inventory system. When I first ran into this it was a bit disconcerting, but then I realized I could actually remove things I never use. So for example, in terms of thrown weapons, I use my grenades, but I never use my tactical option. (Mainly because i can never remember what button to push or what I even have.) When I first maxed out my inventory, I simply got rid of that option and I was all good. I love that. I feel like i have more control over my class now than other CODs in the past. The maps are decent, but more different than spectacular. I also like the fact that you can do games by yourself with robot opponents. Since I&amp;rsquo;ll never get some of the better score streaks going on, this gives me a chance to play around a bit. (And pretend I&amp;rsquo;m really, really good. Which I&amp;rsquo;m not.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over all, I&amp;rsquo;m not quite sure I&amp;rsquo;d recommend this. I know MP is huge for some folks, but I expect both a strong SP and MP in a COD game. (Note I said in a COD game, not all games. I very rarely do MP outside of COD.) I&amp;rsquo;m definitely going to finish the SP for BO2 and hope it improves a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?t=raymondcamden-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=B007XVTR3K&amp;nou=1&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_top&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;bc1=000000&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Halo 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all three, this is my favorite so far. I&amp;rsquo;ve only done SP so far, but the graphics, the art, the game play, is just awesome. The game still has some of the frustrations I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in earlier Halo games. For example, on multiple occasions I&amp;rsquo;ve finished a hard fight, looked around, and realized I had no idea where to go. You only get &amp;ldquo;objective arrows&amp;rdquo; on a few occasions and that just annoys the heck out of me. But luckily I don&amp;rsquo;t get lost all the time and the action is enough to make me get over it pretty quickly. My biggest worry is that I may be almost done. I&amp;rsquo;m about 5 hours in and I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of one person finishing the game in around 6 hours. To me, the story feels like it&amp;rsquo;s just begun, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume that I&amp;rsquo;ve only around &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; or &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, the art is amazing. Multiple times I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself stopping and just looking at the scenery. The amount of detail is outstanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do have one big complaint though. The game doesn&amp;rsquo;t auto-save. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, if you die, you restart in a fairly recent location. (Although with some battles lasting 10+ minutes, it can feel like a bad loss when you die.) But yesterday I had been playing for about two and a half hours when the plug fell out of the socket. (Damn cats.) When I got back into the game  I had lost everything from that morning. Seriously. I thought maybe I was imagining things. There is a Save option in the menu, but it forces you to quit your game. I have no idea why the designers did this. Perhaps saves were too slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what about MP? To be honest, I don&amp;rsquo;t like Halo MP. I know I said that for COD I expect a strong SP and MP experience, but frankly, I&amp;rsquo;m fine with just doing SP with Halo. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to get into Halo MP and people I know and respect love it, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found it just a bit too - well - difficult. If that makes me less of a gamer, well, so be it. I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely give it a try once I finish SP but I don&amp;rsquo;t expect to be playing much MP in this Halo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Halo 4 was purchased via my Amazon Wish List. Unfortunately, Amazon does a pretty poor job of telling me who gets me what. So if you are reading this and your purchased this for me, thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?t=raymondcamden-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=B0050SYX8W&amp;nou=1&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_top&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;bc1=000000&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Got a new Chrome? Got a joystick? Check out the Gamepad API</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/08/01/Got-a-new-Chrome-Got-a-joystick-Check-out-the-Gamepad-API</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 17:08:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/08/01/Got-a-new-Chrome-Got-a-joystick-Check-out-the-Gamepad-API</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest release of Chrome (21.0.1180.57, you know, one of the fifty or so updates that were released over the past week) includes preliminary support for two very cool APIs: WebRTC, the Audio/Video one I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged about before, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dvcs.w3.org/hg/gamepad/raw-file/default/gamepad.html&#34;&gt;Gamepad API&lt;/a&gt;, which gives you access to game controllers via JavaScript. Roll that around a bit in your game for a second and think about how cool that is. When I built a demo with this API a few weeks back and showed my son, he immediately declared that I was the coolest person he knew and that I should sell the app for money. Luckily he isn&amp;rsquo;t reading this blog so he won&amp;rsquo;t see how uncool I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gamepad API contains two basic areas of support. First - you have access to a new property under the navigator object called &amp;ldquo;gamepads&amp;rdquo;. This is an array of all attached gamepads. Since you could - in theory - connect multiple pads via USB it&amp;rsquo;s nice that there is support for working with any number of them. Note that in Chrome this is currently prefixed by &amp;ldquo;webkit&amp;rdquo;, so the actual property is navigator.webkitGamepads. Inspecting the gamepad object gives you access to the name, up to 16 button states, and the axis values for 4 joysticks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part to the API is event driven. This lets you listen for events like a gamepad being connected or a button being pressed. Unfortunately, Chrome doesn&amp;rsquo;t yet support this part of the API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to quickly test if your Chrome is working right with the API? Chrome developer Scott Graham whipped up a super simple demo. Check out the code first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/3230529.js?file=gistfile1.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is a quick screen shot from my machine running it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/ScreenClip107.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally - you can run the JSBin version Scott set up here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jsbin.com/acuhig&#34;&gt;http://jsbin.com/acuhig&lt;/a&gt;. Note that &lt;i&gt;sometimes&lt;/i&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve had to click a button first before it triggered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So given that we don&amp;rsquo;t have the simpler events yet in Chrome, it still isn&amp;rsquo;t terribly difficult to add support to a game. Consider the game below&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/ScreenClip108.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I won&amp;rsquo;t be quitting my job anytime soon to go build games, it was a good way for me to practice with Canvas. (See - I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;i&gt;totally&lt;/i&gt; hate the tag!) I had the logic done already so I was curious how difficult it would be to add in support for the gamepad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, here is a &lt;b&gt;subset&lt;/b&gt; of the code I had initially:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/3230573.js?file=gistfile1.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the event handlers for the keyboard and a loop function that handles animation. The paddle.move() function (not included above) simply checks the value of &amp;ldquo;input&amp;rdquo; to know if it needs to move the paddle left or right. Now here&amp;rsquo;s the modified form of loop to support the gamepad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/3230580.js?file=gistfile1.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is a little over 10 lines of code. And again - when I showed my son this he was amazed and - in all fairness - it does make the game a heck of a lot more fun to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to check it out? Try here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/demos/2012/jul/31/test3.html&#34;&gt;http://www.raymondcamden.com/demos/2012/jul/31/test3.html&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll warn you - the code is messy. Also - I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that I have to reload sometimes for the game to &amp;lsquo;notice&amp;rsquo; the pad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want more information? You can find the spec &lt;a href=&#34;https://dvcs.w3.org/hg/gamepad/raw-file/default/gamepad.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and read up on the API at MDN as well: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.mozilla.org/GamepadAPI&#34;&gt;GamepadAPI&lt;/a&gt;. Note that gamepad support for Firefox is in one build. No, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean the &amp;ldquo;Alpha&amp;rdquo; version. Literally one nightly build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. By the way, to test this I had to pick up (research!) a XBox controller that had a USB connection. All I had were wireless controllers. I picked up the most gaudy one I could find&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/2012-08-01 15.39.25.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Chrome Extension: Diablo 3 Server Checker</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/06/07/New-Chrome-Extension-Diablo-3-Server-Checker</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 12:06:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/06/07/New-Chrome-Extension-Diablo-3-Server-Checker</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I built this because I was trying desperately to procrastinate while finishing an article for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.html5rocks.com&#34;&gt;HTML5Rocks.com&lt;/a&gt;. The Diablo 3 Status Checker does exactly what it says - it pings the English &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.battle.net/d3/en/status&#34;&gt;server status&lt;/a&gt; page and does a bit of regex on the result to see if the American server is up. If it is up - you get a happy face. If not - you get a frowny face. Not exactly rocket science - but it works (especially if you want to avoid writing). Curious about the code? Here is the JavaScript behind it. It is based heavily on one of the existing sample apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/2889374.js?file=gistfile1.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can install it via the CRX I Have hosted here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/enclosures/diablochecker.crx&#34;&gt;http://www.raymondcamden.com/enclosures/diablochecker.crx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to put it up on the Chrome store, but ended up rage-quitting when it asked me for 500 different screen shots of an extension that has two small icons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Review: Kingdoms of Amalur</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/04/29/sunday-review-kingdoms-of-amalur</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 15:04:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/04/29/sunday-review-kingdoms-of-amalur</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?t=raymondcamden-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as1&amp;asins=B0044SA70M&amp;nou=1&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;fc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;lt1=_top&amp;m=amazon&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;bc1=000000&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;f=ifr&#34; style=&#34;width:120px;height:240px;float:left;margin-right:10px;margin-bottom:10px&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 I&amp;rsquo;ve played two really good RPGs over the past few months. Late in 2011, I was immersed in Skyrim. Skyrim is an incredible game. It has a great story. It has great mechanics. And the graphics are - in my opinion - the best you will see on a console today. Heck, even the last Elder Scroll game (Oblivion) has better graphics than most games released today. That being said - as much as I think Skyrim is a better game, I think I had a lot more fun playing Kingdoms of Amalur (KoA). In some ways, I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of Grand Theft Auto versus Saints Row. GTA was an incredibly good looking game with amazing gameplay and artistic direction. It&amp;rsquo;s also a game I never finished. Saints Row - which was certainly not as pretty or dramatic, was just fun, and relatively simple to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I did finish Skyrim (I&amp;rsquo;ve got 110+ hours in it), I found KoA to be a heck of a lot of fun and just a pleasure to finish. The graphics are fine (not great, not bad) and the sound is forgettable. The RPG elements though work real well. Like most modern RPGs you aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly locked into a class and you can even reset all your character decisions during the game. While game play is pretty much divided between stealth (finesse), fighting (might) and magic (sorcery), you can create many different combinations of these to fit your particular style. (I chose might/sorcery.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing the game does very well is providing you with a sense of continuous improvement. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about just advancing levels but an overall sense of growth into a kick-ass adventurer. Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve finished the main game, I&amp;rsquo;m planning on getting the DLC just as an excuse so I can see how far my character can progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway - if you are looking for a fun RPG and are a bit worried about a Skyrim-level commitment, consider picking up KoA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. It has been a while since I posted a review. Sorry - going to try to get back into the habit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I cheated Mozilla&#39;s new HTML5 Game</title>
      <link>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/03/28/How-I-cheated-Mozillas-new-HTML5-Game</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 15:03:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.raymondcamden.com/2012/03/28/How-I-cheated-Mozillas-new-HTML5-Game</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not advocating cheating as a good thing. I&amp;rsquo;m not insinuating that Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s code was somehow lacking (actually the code is pretty kick ass). Nor am I trying to pretend I&amp;rsquo;m some super hacker. Rather - I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share how I modified Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s new game to cheat as a way of demonstrating things you have to look out for when coding HTML5-based games. Also - my &lt;i&gt;very first&lt;/i&gt; programming experience was pretty similar. I had to learn hex so I could edit my Bard&amp;rsquo;s Tale game saves via a disk editor on my Apple 2e. I figured a legacy as rich as that deserves a rebirth. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So first - some context. Yesterday Mozilla announced the launch of &lt;a href=&#34;http://browserquest.mozilla.org&#34;&gt;Browser Quest&lt;/a&gt;. This is a multiplayer online roll playing game. The mechanics aren&amp;rsquo;t terribly complex (non-gamers should give it a try), but it is a pretty cool example of what can be done with HTML5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/ScreenClip55.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply connect to the site, enter a name, cross your fingers (it is a bit overwhelmed right now), and start playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/ScreenClip56.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s really cool is that Mozilla has also open sourced the entire game - both the front end client and back-end technology. You can peruse the code here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mozilla/BrowserQuest&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mozilla/BrowserQuest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I played it for a bit (research!) and noticed right away that they were using LocalStorage. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a Chrome extension (&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/bpidlidmmmnapeldonddkjmmjkpeiabi&#34;&gt;LocalStorage Monitor&lt;/a&gt;) that highlights when a site is using LocalStorage and lets me examine the contents quickly. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I saw on the site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/ScreenClip57.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing I noticed - my inventory was stored in LocalStorage. That meant I could modify my inventory. After looking at the code, I realized they had a simple list of swords and armors that were ranked by a simple numeric index. If you gave yourself the top weapon/armor, then you would be set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So step one was to pop into console and copy out the value:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
copy(localStorage[&amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo;])
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This copied the value (a JSON string) into my clipboard. I pasted it into notepad, and simply edited the two values:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
{&amp;ldquo;hasAlreadyPlayed&amp;rdquo;:true,&amp;ldquo;player&amp;rdquo;:{&amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;Romana&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;weapon&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;goldensword&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;armor&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;goldenarmor&amp;rdquo;,&amp;ldquo;image&amp;rdquo;:&amp;ldquo;data:image/png;base64,deleted&amp;rdquo;},&amp;ldquo;achievements&amp;rdquo;:{&amp;ldquo;unlocked&amp;rdquo;:[2,5,11,6],&amp;ldquo;ratCount&amp;rdquo;:3,&amp;ldquo;skeletonCount&amp;rdquo;:1,&amp;ldquo;totalKills&amp;rdquo;:5,&amp;ldquo;totalDmg&amp;rdquo;:11,&amp;ldquo;totalRevives&amp;rdquo;:0}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the string, went back into console, and did&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
localStorage[&amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo;] = (pasted my string here)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reloaded the page, and voila - I&amp;rsquo;m an Epic Avenger of Mighty Awesomeness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.raymondcamden.com/images/ScreenClip58.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to repeat - I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to diminish anything Mozilla did here. It&amp;rsquo;s a great demo. Just don&amp;rsquo;t forget that localStorage, like any client data, is inherently insecure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. Wondering why you see a 5Tagger character and Romana? Just different tests, that&amp;rsquo;s all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>